Podcasting 2.0 for May 20th, 2022, episode
86. We're stocking salad dressing.
Hey, everybody.
Welcome to Podcasting 2.0.
It's a podcast, but it's also the
official board meeting of Podcasting 2.0.
We talk about everything that's
going on with podcastindex.org.
We got the podcast namespace, the
podcast standards, and, of course,
everything that we're discussing
over there at podcastindex.social.
I'm Adam Curry here in the heart of the
Texas Hill Country, and in Alabama,
he doesn't need a camera to look handsome.
Ladies and gentlemen, say hello to my
friend on the other end, Mr. Dave Jones.
Handsome is my middle name.
Yeah.
It's Dave H. Jones.
That's right.
Yes.
H.
Hey, have you ever heard a Brit say H?
Yeah, they always say H.
They say H. I know.
It's the weirdest thing.
I remember when I was doing
my helicopter training,
and one of my instructors was, what
was his name, was it Captain Dan?
No, Pete.
Pete?
No.
Anyway.
Pete.
I don't know if it was Pete or not.
Anyway, this guy, he kept
saying, you know, all right,
just go ahead and land it on the H.
Where?
On the H.
What's the H?
Is that like some thing in the
airport that I don't know about?
A H?
Is that a special?
The H!
You see the big white H?
Oh, H!
Okay, I got you.
No, it's me and my son, the invalid,
has had me watching every episode
of Top Gear, you know, ever made.
Oh, you hadn't seen them all?
You hadn't, you weren't a watcher?
There's like 20, I mean, like, we've
watched them throughout the years,
but there's like, you know, like
20 seasons or something like that.
And so, I hadn't seen them all,
so we're going back and watching
all the ones we never saw before.
Yeah, that was what they were, they
were saying something last night,
and I actually called it out last night.
I was like, why does he keep saying H?
Yeah, well, now you know.
Well, my son is super into cars, and
he learned everything he, I'm sorry,
I'm eating chocolate.
Yeah, I did.
You know, that's very unprofessional.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
It matches the rest of us.
It matches the rest of the show.
And the, so he learned all of his, like,
car terminology and
everything from Top Gear.
Mm-hmm.
So, I mean, he was calling things like,
he was calling the
windshield the windscreen.
Windscreen, the fascia.
And the hood, the bonnet.
The bonnet, the fascia.
Yeah.
That's the dashboard.
It's not a dashboard.
I learned all that when I bought my Rolls.
Mm.
I had a 1979 Silver Shadow 2.
Oh, wow, that's a beautiful car.
Yeah, Brewster Green, so it's
the British Racing Green.
I bought it off a guy in
Florida, original owner.
I think it had, like, 17,000
miles on it or something.
And I bought it in Manhattan,
and I drove it into Manhattan
every day from New Jersey for,
God, I don't know, five, six, seven years.
Maybe longer than that.
That's a heavy car.
Oh, yeah.
That thing weighs, like, 12 tons.
Yeah, it had, you know,
big, I think it was a V12.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
And it was crazy, because
everything was drive-by wires,
so the steering wheel was really thin
and, you know, really tiny, but
the hydraulics was so fantastic.
I mean, you could turn that thing
on a dime with just your pinky.
Now, of course, if the engine
wasn't running, you were screwed.
Yeah.
See, I don't want anything between
my steering wheel and the wheels.
Yeah, no, that's not how it rolled.
In fact, the thing was so
quiet that I was quite
irritated by the ticking of the clock.
Wow.
Yeah, and that was, you had a little
clock in there in the fascia.
And it was a 72?
79.
Okay.
And that thing had pickup, man.
It was unbelievable.
And when the transmission
went out, believe it or not,
I rolled it right up to Lee Miles.
It was a GM transmission in that thing.
Oh, so they could just,
they just swapped that out.
Yeah.
That's like a, yeah,
that's like a weekend job.
1,200 bucks, you know.
Yeah.
You know, brakes, brakes cost me 7,000
because, you know, they were the, the.
Yeah, the transmission, transmission
was cheaper than the, the, the dash.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
You want to hear a douchebag
story about that car?
Oh, I would love to hear a
douchebag story about that.
I'm looking at it on, online,
by the way, and it's beautiful.
Mine, my actual car?
The Silver Shadow 2.
Oh, no, because I think there's
probably a picture of me with it.
Oh, is there?
Okay.
Yeah, I'm sure.
So, I was driving home from MTV
on a Friday afternoon, well,
it was maybe a Thursday afternoon.
I thought it was a Friday afternoon,
and the Lincoln Tunnel's just jammed.
It's, you know, and anyone who would,
you know, lived or worked in Manhattan,
you know, you're going out of the
tunnel on a Friday afternoon.
You could be in an hour and a half
just sitting there before you get,
even get into the tunnel.
And I'm low on gas.
And I'm like, I'll be okay,
because I know there's a gas
station at the other end on the
Jersey side of the
tunnel, so it'll be cool.
And, of course, by the time I'm
in the tunnel, I'm out of gas.
And so, there I am.
It's, you know, it's, it's 90
degrees, and I'm stuck in the tunnel.
The only way, and, and
the tunnel was two-way.
So, one, one lane was
going towards Jersey,
and the other lane was
coming into Manhattan.
So, they had to stop all the
traffic from the other end,
bring the push car all the way
around to come through the
tunnel back to me, and push me.
And now, again, no, no, no power steering,
because the engine's not running.
And this guy's just pushing.
And this is the tunnel.
I got this 12, you know, 12-ton car.
I'm like, oh, try not to hit the
cones, try not to hit the side.
But I had my MTV leather
jacket on, and I had my hair,
and I was the most hated
man in the tri-state area.
Fucking Curry!
Must be nice, Curry!
Yeah, people throwing
shit at me, you know.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, the funny, I always
take pictures of when
I need to help other people with their
car, because, you know,
I drive the 65 Ford.
Yeah.
And more than once, this has happened.
And I have a really nice picture of me
jumping off an Audi from my 65 Ford.
Oh, nice.
And I'm like, you know,
this is just sweet.
The irony of this is just beautiful.
I like it.
Oh, man.
Looks like we are lit once
again on this episode.
You are live on video?
Yes, we are.
Yeah, well, we're lit in two ways.
We're streaming live, and that, of course,
now works in CurioCaster and Podverse.
I am also streaming live to NoAgendaTube,
which is a PeerTube instance.
At least, I was.
I don't know if it's working.
This is, it's all just a test.
I got a little camera here.
I'm just showing the
equipment, not my face.
No one needs that.
Let me try that.
I'm going to get off my local
Wi-Fi and try to connect on LTE,
so I won't miss my bandwidth.
Okay.
I actually got an error.
Let me see.
Oh, no.
I didn't even know NaTube supported live.
Yeah.
This was all new.
I think it's RMTP.
Is that it?
RMTP?
RTMP?
RTMP.
Yeah.
Let me just see if this works.
Real-time media something.
Protocol?
Yeah, let's say that.
Real-time media protocol?
Yeah, that sounds right.
Okay.
I restarted the broadcast,
so I don't know if it works.
Here it is.
Adam Curry live.
Yeah.
Does it look like I'm live?
You look a lot like a black screen.
Yeah, I got errors.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
Well, I'll just keep broadcasting and maybe
Alex can do something on the back end.
I don't know.
Jiggle the handle, Alex.
Jiggle the handle, man.
It's all just a test.
You know, we're getting ready.
This is what it is.
This is the definition of
running with scissors.
So, speaking of scissors.
Uh-oh.
Yes.
I got Sovereign Feeds
working with the webhook.
Ooh.
We need to talk about this.
Okay.
So, let's just go through the issues.
What we've learned.
And today, I think I did properly upload
the RSS feed with the pending tag.
Then, we did the live tag, which
is another RSS feed upload for me.
I haven't looked at if it worked.
I didn't look at any.
You know, because we know
the caching is a problem.
And we are going to make this into a
one, I guess, a one-click operation now?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
So, the first, let me see.
First, I guess we need to make sure
that this actually worked first.
I mean, like, with the live
notification and everything.
Mm-hmm.
Because I didn't get anything
on my phone from Podverse.
Let's see.
Podverse.
Let me go check.
Podcasting 2.0.
I want to see if there's
a live item up there.
Yeah, I see.
Oh, yeah.
I see it.
Okay.
So, it works, right?
Yeah, I figured it would work.
I figured it would work.
I didn't get a notification, though.
I may be still in the beta.
You mean a Podverse notification?
Mm-hmm.
This is going to be so effing cool
when all the bits are bolted together.
It's going to be crazy, man.
So, how will this webhook work?
So, I've got sovereign feeds.
That's how I create the feeds.
I guess I just add a
parameter for a webhook,
and that goes to some magic
you've put on a server somewhere?
Yeah, so… A URL, I guess,
is what I have to call.
Let me find it, and
I'll shoot you the URL.
It's podcasting.
So, I went into sovereign
feeds and set a webhook URL,
and you're going to need
to set that same one.
So, let me see if I can pull it up here.
For some reason, it's not showing mine.
I'll send it to you after the show.
So, the way it works is you
can set a URL per podcast,
and then when you go into the webhook
section for that podcast, it's like sticky.
So, you can have one for each show,
or a different webhook for each show.
And then, so, I rolled a server on Linode,
just a five-buck server that's
going to do nothing but this.
That way, we can sort of
security isolate it by itself.
Mm-hmm.
Because there is some risk here of letting,
you know, the world send you things.
Yeah.
Especially sending you feeds
that can also change your feed.
Yeah.
Oh, one of those things.
Yeah, one of those things.
So, Stephen's got a little
bit of security baked in.
There's a webhook URL,
and then there's an authorization header
that can just take a random string.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
Now, how do I get that?
Oh, sorry.
That's, that was, yeah, I went to check.
You ghosted on me for a second.
No, I'm here.
So, then, if you put in that, you
put in the URL of the server,
which is that new box
that I rolled at Linode,
and then you put in the authorization
string, it will, when you build the feed,
you go over there, and the final thing
you do is you hit the create RSS file,
and then there's an
option to send to server.
Ah, okay.
Do you see that option in there?
Or you may not if there's
no webhook entered.
Let me see.
Webhooks.
Webhook link.
Secret.
Yeah, you have, there's that,
and then you should have,
when you hit the create RSS file,
there's a new button there
that says send to server.
Okay, but first, I don't
have the link or the secret.
Gotcha.
Okay, so, yeah, it's not going
to show up for you then.
All right.
No.
So, that's how it works.
So, you'll hit the send to server button,
and it will send the entire RSS feed,
and it'll send it as a post parameter
to that URL, that webhook URL,
with the authorization
token that you specified
as an authorization header in the request.
So, that, what we do on the box is
accept that it's a JSON payload.
So, we accept the JSON payload,
decode the XML out of it,
and then turn around and post
it to object storage on Linode.
And so, we have a bucket in the
New Jersey Linode data center.
We have an S3 bucket up there.
It's just, New Jersey has
lots of buckets, Dave.
I used to live there, so I'm just
saying, this is buckets galore.
But yes, in the data center, gotcha.
Yes, yeah.
Buckets of good things this time.
So, you upload it to the
feeds.podcastindex.org bucket.
Yeah.
And it will create pc20.xml with
the RSS feed in it that was sent.
And that is fronted by Cloudflare,
which is proxying and caching
everything coming in to that URL.
So, it will be the new
URL for our show will
be feeds.podcastindex.org slash pc20.xml.
But, what I'll get Mark Void Zero to
do is to point that at Cloudflare.
Is do a redirect on our existing
URL, where when things hit that,
it will just 302 redirect over to the URL.
Oh, okay.
Now, 302, so will people be subscribing
to that then in the future?
People will continue to
subscribe and check the old one,
but it will always end up at the new one.
Because the 302 is just a temporary.
There's no one who's going to see that
and go, oh, that's the permanent.
I got to do that.
Yeah.
I didn't want to do that because
I was, at least not for now.
No.
One day when we think, okay, this thing's
solid as a rock, then we'll flip it.
But, yeah.
No, for now, it's just temporary redirect.
This should, I mean, I tested it four or
five times yesterday, and it was cool.
It worked.
It worked like a charm.
Like, you hit that send to
server, and within three seconds,
the new feed or XML is up there.
Cool.
Yeah.
I think this gets rid
of our caching issue.
Yeah.
I mean, yeah, because people will
be hitting a new feed, basically.
Sure.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Yeah, and the caching within
Cloudflare is very straightforward.
I mean, you know, it keeps track of an
e-tag header on the object storage side.
So, that thing, if that updates,
you just get the new feed.
Mm-hmm.
The one thing, also, what Stephen B.
did was he put in this, he's
got this feature where, like…
That's Phoebe, the podcast dog.
Sorry.
I noticed Phoebe.
Yes.
Broke through this.
This is the gate buster.
She sure did.
So, he had, he put in a feature where
you can, like, hand back a payload,
a JSON object, I mean, not a payload,
a JSON object, like, as a status.
So, you can say, you can just hand
back, when he calls the webhook,
you give him back something.
And, you know, we kind of went back and
forth a little bit on what that would be.
And he wants, like, he wants a
stat, some sort of status, like,
well, did it succeed?
Did it fail?
Right.
But then, also, he wants back a
pod ping equals true or false.
Uh-huh.
So, if you hand back the pod ping true…
Oh, Phoebe, be quiet.
Yeah.
He'll, uh, he'll pod ping for you.
I can get mine going, too,
if you want to do that.
We should, we should double team here.
Yes.
Phoebe, Phoebe, Phoebe, it's okay, girl.
Good girl.
Come here.
Yeah, so, anyway, that's,
that's the way that works.
Um, and it, it, it means, it makes, so,
it makes sense to pod ping
right after you hand that off.
But in order to send the pod ping, you
have to know where the file ended up.
So, like, when he sends, uh, when he
sends the webhook with the XML in it,
you're going to end up, um, like, that,
that feed, that feed XML could go anywhere.
You don't, he's just sending
it blindly to a URL.
And so, that, ultimately, he has no way
of knowing where that feed is going to,
is going to, like, end up and finally.
So, what we figured out is, is we
can hand back the, sort of, uh,
I'm handing him back
public underscore URL, and, um,
that's where the final feed ended up.
And so, he can just take, so,
if you hand back public URL
equals the URL of the feed and
pod ping equals true,
then he will just turn around and
send a pod ping to that feed URL,
with that feed URL as the,
as the payload immediately.
So, this should solve, like, the pod
ping issue and the feed updating issue.
So, going forward, like, when, when this
is, when we've got this nailed down,
I mean, it, it already works.
I mean, we, we can, we can start
doing this after the show, um,
when it's all nailed down,
we can, you'll, you'll just
be able to go through,
build the feed and sovereign feeds,
um, save it, and then hit send
to server, and it should, Bill,
it should send it to the
right place, and pod ping it both, and
you won't, there's no extra steps.
Holy moly.
This is cool.
Yeah.
That's pretty awesome.
Really cool.
Yeah.
If it, this feels like the beginning of
the, taking this from, uh, you know,
a box of scissors
to taking it to, like, something that's
automated, like, you know what I mean?
Like, this is, this is
how it begins, you, you,
you throw all the crap on the floor, and
then you start building
it up into little piles.
And this is what this is.
Yeah.
This is the start of the piles.
Oh, man.
Well, we're going to get there.
I mean, uh, and I, I keep watching, uh,
uh, Sir Spencer's stuff, who is just,
I mean, he's, he's got it down now.
He's, he's got it all figured out.
Yeah.
I mean, it's, it's just unbelievable.
I don't know what he's doing.
I don't know what, what tools
he's using or what exactly.
Maybe he's just hand coding
it like a, like a cowboy.
I don't know.
No, I don't know.
It could be.
I don't know if he's used.
I don't, I don't think he's
using sovereign feeds.
We do have, um, gosh, the, uh, remember
I told you about, uh, the Yensa show,
Robert Yensa.
Yeah.
How's that going?
That's going very well with they, so they,
they, I think they built their own web
hook so they can now publish directly
from, uh, from sovereign feeds and, and,
and now on their website,
they're promoting,
I think they're promoting
pod verse and they chose to,
they wanted to promote.
I said, Hey, could you add a new podcast
apps.com there, which they'll do.
Um, so they're already, uh,
they're already rolling.
And, and I said, well, here's the link.
If you want to, you know,
get your wallet and get rolling
because fountain of course, you
know, is a great, since they
already familiar with that.
Um, and I expect them to
do that, uh, next week.
Oh, nice.
And that's going to be awesome.
I think it really will be.
I mean, uh, the guy's got to reach.
He really does.
Um, uh, we got to do.
Okay.
I see what happened.
We, we have a duplicate feed
for podcasting 2.0 actually.
Yes.
There's a reason for that.
That is, that is on my list to talk about.
Oh, well, uh, I'm all ears.
Shall I tell you?
Well, I've been, uh, I've been talking
with, uh, Cameron, uh, Cameron is,
I think he's just at Cameron
on podcast index.social.
He is the guy behind the IPFS
podcasting app in Umbral.
Okay.
All right.
So I set up, uh, I, I, I ran the
IPFS podcasting app on Umbral.
I had no idea what I was doing, of course.
Um, and you know, uh,
I think all of my feeds were already in
there and I just said, oh, these feeds.
Okay.
I'll pin them.
So whatever, uh, the feed is in the, in
the files there, they'll be cached on my,
on my Umbral.
And as I was just watching this network
kind of come to life over the 24 hours,
you just see all these different episodes,
people who have invented many
of the episodes of all of
the, my feeds, but let's just
focus on the podcasting 2.0.
I've been downloaded
quite a number of times.
And so now that duplicate
feed, if you, uh,
if you look at the feed
on a podcast index.org,
and this is of course a problem because
it's, it's named exactly the same thing.
This is, this is something
that needs to be fixed.
If you look at it, it has, uh,
an IPFS gateway enclosure.
So that's a, just an HTT, HTTP
IPFS podcasting.org or.com.
Let me see.
What is it?
Um, dot, dot net.
What number, what feed ID is it?
I can, do you have that?
Uh, cause I'm not seeing it.
Well, it was in there
and then it went away.
I pinged you about it.
I said, Hey, it was in there.
Hold on.
I can.
So I can kill it.
Well, you can kill it.
Sure.
No, did I mean, say, did I kill it?
I don't know.
Well, I, I asked you if there was some D
dupe, automatic D dupe thing in there.
Cause it showed up as
a complete duplicate.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So I figured that there
was some D dupe in there.
Um, hold on a second.
Let me, uh, let me bring it up here.
Cause, um, yeah, the D, the D
dupe, the D duper scripts now run.
And I don't know what
they do half the time.
Um, if something happens and I have
to go back and like, you know,
it's, it's very similar.
It's very similar to the
Luna coin automated crap.
I mean, like one of these
days where I'm going
to wake up and there's gonna
be no feeds in the database.
And I'll be like, Oh God, what happened?
Okay.
So podcasting 2.0, the feed is, okay.
I'm going to find it for you.
But I can just dump the feed URL into
podcast index.org and it'll find it for me,
I believe.
Oh, cool.
Okay.
Yeah.
No, cool is that's, I get to say cool.
Cause you built it that way.
No, and I gotta, I gotta give you, I
gotta give a comic strip blogger that he,
he said, he said we should support
search searching for URLs.
And that has like saved
my life a million times.
Oh, cool.
I'm going to, so it's no
longer in the database.
So I've just put it in the signal chat.
So now if you look at, if
you look at that feed, uh,
I'll put it in the chat room so people
can take a look at it so they can
play along, play along chatters.
There you go.
Uh, okay.
Oh, wow.
There's a bunch.
Yeah.
Uh, this, do you see
the alternate website?
Do you see the alt, the alternate URL?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
The ipfspodcasting.net, blah, blah, blah.
Right, but are you, look at,
look at the alternate enclosure.
Alternate enclosure.
Is this the, is this the XML?
Are you looking at the XML?
You probably have to hit the XML.
Here we go.
I got it.
Okay.
Uh, alternate enclosure.
Oh, let's go to episode 85.
There should be an alternate.
There it is.
Alternate enclosure.
Yeah.
Yeah, I see it.
So not only does he have the gateway,
which is ipfspodcasting.net,
which is a regular
HTTP call, but he has
the alternate enclosure,
which is an IPFS with just the the hash.
I see it.
Yeah.
So what is this?
I mean, like, how, how,
how is this being created?
It's fucking magic.
Like, yeah, but, yeah,
but for reals though.
Okay.
So, so you go to ipfspodcasting.net and
you don't need to install anything in your
umbrella.
We, we, we want, we want more people
running nodes for obvious reasons.
You, uh, you, uh, you, um, verify
your feed, which is, you know,
done through your feed, uh,
email, uh, address and,
and then it ingests it and then
it start and then it will start
to, you know, it's there.
And then the minute someone hits
one of those, uh, one of those, uh,
enclosures, then that
gets pinned in the network
for 48 hours and it'll,
it'll stay pinned unless
someone has them all.
So I pin everything on my feed.
So they're going to be there no matter
what, because they're ultimately,
they're on my umbral.
Um, but if no one requests the item
after 48 hours, then it, uh, buyers,
then someone would have
to request it again.
It would come from the original,
which would theoretically be, um, uh,
from the, from the
regular server, I guess.
Yeah.
Uh, oh no, no, I'm sorry.
Uh, it would, it's the IPFS gateway.
No, it would be from my umbral.
So, so you're, so you're hosting the.
The enclosures on your umbral
or the feed or the feed XML?
Both.
Well, no, no, no, the feed, the
feed, yeah, the feed XML is in IPFS.
So I, I put it on my umbral.
That's where it starts.
Although technically it was art.
Someone had already done that.
I guess Cameron had already put
that, all of that in there.
Then if you say, okay, I want to
pin either the most recent, uh,
enclosures or all enclosures,
you can make that selection
and that's then all.
Now anyone can do that.
So you could do the same on your umbral.
Now we have two, two sources.
Uh, okay.
Okay.
So I can, I can, um, sort of.
What do you call it?
Back, back you up, so to speak.
Yeah.
Pinning.
Exactly.
Yeah.
So one thing that's
interesting about what I'm
looking at here on this
page is that there's
every episode back to episode seven.
Where did those come from?
Oh, so he's been, exactly.
He's, he's been experimenting with
this for a while using our feed.
So he got, before I broke our feed
and, uh, and lost all the episodes,
it had already, so this is all on IPFS.
These are all, uh, basically hashed,
hashed enclosures that are just out there.
Cause this is quite helpful.
It's helpful if you lose shit.
Yeah, exactly.
Like, this is cool.
Yeah.
Okay.
This, this, uh, brings up a good
point that I want to, uh, Stephen B.
We need, when we need to talk, we
need to talk, we need to talk.
Um, this is, I would,
I would highly suggest putting this
feature in immediately, uh, version
history, sort of keep a copy of the
XML for the last X number of saves,
you know, going back, I don't
know, three weeks or a month just
to be sure that you can revert back and
pick up a lost feed in case you need to.
I, I'm going to do that on
the webhook server myself.
I'm just going to, every time it comes in,
I'm just going to
timestamp a copy and keep
it in a, in a, in a directory,
but it would be really user
friendly to have that feature
be built in the user interface.
Does that, I mean, if that way, if
you totally screw something up,
you can just revert.
Right.
Yeah.
Do that now.
Cause that's somebody's one of these days,
somebody's going to love
you for that feature.
Well, he already put the save in, which
is, was a godsend, you know, just so that
if you're doing work and you save it and
you lose it, you know, you're, you know,
it's stored in the browser.
Well, you know, we, we had to
do this in a frame controller.
We had to do the version history.
Yes, we did.
Yes.
Oh my God.
I remember not having it.
Yeah.
And you can accidentally hit control
S and you're like, Oh God, no.
What did I just do?
Bad, bad, bad.
Yes, exactly.
Um, so what we also,
you know, what we need,
what I think will be
cool is if we can get,
um, IPFS native into some of the apps.
Hmm.
That's the client side of IPFS.
I know nothing about.
Look at me.
I mean, isn't it just, I mean,
isn't it just another called except
you're just calling to IPFS space?
Yeah.
I think I, I mean, I know
how to do it on the,
like from the command line on something,
but I'm, I guess I'm, when I say I
know nothing about the client side,
I mean like, uh, there's
gotta be libraries out there
and stuff that you can pull in.
Right, right, right, right.
And then I don't know, I don't know, I
don't know what that landscape looks like.
Um, maybe, uh, maybe,
so who is IPFS podcast?
You said Cameron, who is this?
Uh, at Cameron on, uh,
on podcast index.social.
Oh, oh yeah.
Okay.
So maybe, I mean, Cameron
can give us some help here.
If he's the podcast, he's the IPFS guy.
That's, that's it.
He's now the IPFS guy.
Oh yeah.
No, he, he is the IPFS guy.
It's not now.
He's always been the IP.
He's just, he's the IPFS guy.
He's just it.
That's what he is.
That's just him, man.
He's the IPFS guy.
That was, he's awesome.
Um, yeah.
So he can, he can maybe
give us a clue on, uh,
on library support and that kind of thing
for the, uh, for the client side apps.
It's a good idea.
Yeah.
Let me just see.
Uh, so we got a lot of work to do on
this clearly, but I'm so excited by,
by the, uh,
by all the capabilities.
Um, let's see.
Did you see that, uh, did you
see that Podverse put Albie?
Yes, of course I did.
We need to talk about it.
So where, where exactly are we?
Because I'm, here's the,
here's the funny thing.
I know that, uh, that they're
doing something interesting
because I'm getting a
lot of 10 sat boosts.
Yes, I saw that.
And I don't know if these are, but
they are all, there's boostagrams.
I don't, they're not doing
streaming sats though yet, I guess.
Just only boostagrams at the time being?
Looks like it.
Yeah.
It looks like single one-off boostagrams.
And when I get something from Podverse
on a boostagram, I don't have a name or,
or a episode title,
just the podcast name, amount, and
there'll be a message or not, uh, but not,
not who it's from, not the episode.
So that's just parameters, I guess,
that just aren't quite, aren't being,
aren't being sent through yet.
Can you please explain to me, and I
don't know why, but I don't, I'm just,
I'm sort of having a difficulty
understanding Albie a little bit.
It's probably just me being
distracted, but what, what is,
is Albie a wallet or is it a
connection to your wallet,
to a, to a remote wallet?
So Albie, first of all, is an extension.
That's what it is.
It's a browser extension.
So, uh, this will never work on mobile.
In my opinion.
It's just, it's for a browser.
It's a browser extension.
So you can connect to their node.
There could, there could,
Phoebe, come here.
You can connect to their custodial node,
which is the default for
99% of all people, but you
can also very similar to, um, Guillerme's,
uh, uh, extension, uh, pod station.
You can, you can connect it to
your external node or wallet or,
you know, whatever else.
But, uh, the default, which is
using their custodial system.
So you, you get a wallet on the
custodial wallet on their node.
So they're doing key send on the back end.
So you're using an LN URL,
uh, to make the payment.
And because they can do key send,
you can use LN URL pay, uh, and,
and it'll go straight
from key send from their node
to whatever the splits are.
And I think the splits are working too.
I believe I'm not 100% sure.
I think so.
Must, they must be actually.
So whatever Mitch did with,
uh, what's the guy's name?
Bombi, Boombi?
Boomy.
Yeah.
They did something good.
They're definitely doing something right.
Now Boomy is the, uh, he's
the get Albie developer.
Yeah.
I think it's, it's, I think
it's just two German.
It's two German dudes.
Oh.
I think so.
Okay.
So that means they're sort of, they're
playing sort of the role of, uh,
Brian, of Brian's hive.
Pod ping.
String it together.
Yeah.
Beautiful.
There's a can on one end,
a can on the other end,
and there's some stuff in the middle
that connects, that
connects them together.
Now, what I like, what I
like about this is this
is a way to create new
podcast experiences.
So this could be integrated, you know,
in essence on any page that
has a value block information,
you know, so, so it can be, it can be
utilized for many, many different things.
And I believe I saw a GitHub
repo that Mitch put together.
So that you can pop up a 2.0 payment
information on any web page.
You can embed it, I believe.
So I think you're, I think you're right.
So this is where I'm still going
after 40% of women who play,
who play podcasts on a web page.
However, you know, as I
was thinking through this,
I think of the 40% of women who don't
use a podcast app but play
something from a web page,
90% of that is going to be on Safari,
which of course is not going to work with
Albie because of the extension issue.
And none of this is really a problem
moving forward, Dave, you know,
stuff is going to get better.
But I just love the idea that at
least we do have a desktop, you know,
option that would
integrate with more than just
podcasting 2.0, but it integrates with,
you know, other lightning
payments and, oh God, tipping,
you know, that kind of stuff.
So this, this is why, one of
the reasons I brought this up,
there's untapped potential
here for like, you're,
like you're talking about.
But one, one thing that
I think that I had an
idea for a few times already was some sort
of, you have this idea of like dynamic ad
insertion where you're pulling in ads from
other podcasts.
Have you seen, have you heard
this where there'll be like,
you're listening to a podcast and
a Gary Arndt show does this, uh,
everything everywhere daily.
Yeah, it's just using, it's using, uh, ad
insertion technology, except instead of an
ad, it's a promo for a different podcast.
Yeah.
And that's the point I'm trying to get at.
It's the, it's the promo for
other podcasts aspect of it.
That's cool.
So you have, um, uh, Gary and
Gary may be doing this by hand.
I don't know if he's using DAI, but I
was thinking you could have like this,
some sort of like marketplace or
like, uh, ad, ad clearing house.
Uh, and I'm calling them an
ad, but what it's really is.
Like there's clips from other shows.
This is all very mushy.
Okay.
So, so yeah.
I won't, I won't shoot you down just yet.
Yes.
Thank you.
Uh, wait till I fall on the ground.
Then shoot me.
You got, um, I'm thinking
some sort of thing where
you can put a blit in your show or attach
it and maybe to, um, to a clip or a
soundbite or something or a trailer,
maybe that's even better.
Attach it to a trailer.
And then, uh, it goes in.
There's a, there's a, another party
that's watching for these things.
As we find them in the fees,
we're putting them into this, uh,
sort of database of, of this marketplace.
Then, um, then other, other
podcasts can pull that down.
And every time they get a listen on that
ad or on that, I keep calling them an ad.
It's more like a, like a clip or
a trailer or something like that.
Every time they get it,
they'll, you can send off us.
You can send off a payment
to the original feed owner.
Or to the one that played it.
That played it.
Right, right.
The owner could send a split to the
podcast that sucked it down and played it.
Ah, okay.
You see what I'm saying?
So, like you, all these people could
submit, could submit clips or little,
little soundbites
and to a, with, with a split or excuse
me, with a, um, um, with a, with a,
yeah, with it, with like a source wallet
and then, um, with like an invoice,
maybe like an open invoice.
And then these ones that pay it, that play
it can pull, can like charge the invoice.
I'm not sure how this all works.
Like I said, this is all very mushy,
but I'm thinking there's
a possibility to do some
sort of like shared marketplace
of communal, like ad.
I'm going to play an ad
for my show on your show.
And then I'm going to pay you some
stats for the privilege of doing it.
Um, and all this, do you, can you envision
a way this would work or am I good?
No, no, I can completely
envision what you're saying.
And I, and I understand this.
I have fundamental issues.
I don't believe this works.
I don't believe this works as promotion.
I don't believe in the
interrupt of ad model.
I have a whole bunch of, of issues separate
from the, from the technical piece.
Right.
If that makes any sense.
I mean, this, this whole automating
of discovery, I, I just don't see it.
I've, uh, I helped invent this medium.
I've been doing it for a long time.
The way people find out about
podcasts is someone tells you, Hey,
there's this cool podcast.
And then they go find it.
They go find it part is, is where there's
opportunity, but I don't want my feed in.
I don't want interruptions with,
with, you know, but for a while,
I don't know if he's still doing it.
Maybe it was because he was trying to
figure this out, uh, on, on pod news.
There would be a trailer
after the pod news.
So I hated that too.
And the main problem, the main reason
I hated it, there was no context.
I didn't know all of a sudden you
just get dropped into a trailer.
You know, it's something else.
If, if, if the host says, Hey, uh,
there's a trailer coming up
with this great podcast.
I think you should listen to,
uh, it's this, this, and this.
And then, and so that would have been
something, but then trailers were three,
four minutes uninteresting, uh,
unclear, not good trailers.
So I'm trying to figure
out what, you know,
is there really a benefit
to doing anything of this?
If the host, oh, there we go.
It works again.
Uh, well, you know, in the
chat, ice cube soup says, uh,
the way to do this already exists
and, uh, comes to your bloggers.
Exactly.
Send us a 15,000 sets and
we promote your podcast.
Thank you.
Yes.
That's the point.
I guess I'm thinking less of, and
here's where I'm being not clear.
I'm thinking less of the
automated insertion part.
I don't like that either.
So I'm thinking less of that and
more of just like there being,
I think in my mind, comic
strip blogger is very, is sort
of what I am envisioning there.
There, there needs to
be some way that I can
like hear part of some cool thing from the
show and then get some stats for it.
So like there needs to be a way,
and this can't be done in the TLV.
It's just too big.
It's too much data.
So if CSB is wanting to have, you know,
he could send us a boost
and for us to play, you
know, do this thing on the show.
But I want to be able to
also access some sort
of maybe audio from his show or something.
Yeah, but this is, yes.
Yeah.
I just don't understand why.
Oh, seriously.
I don't.
No, I get it.
I get it.
I mean, we, we want, we once played
a little piece of AI.cooking.
I don't, I don't know if it
was on podcast, uh, podcast.
Maybe it was on, uh, Curry and the Keeper.
And we're like, okay, no.
No, but it was great.
Gregory William Forsyth.
Yes, who is a, who, by the way,
does fantastic end of show mixes.
This dude is interesting.
Um, so, you know, it's more like
all of these ideas for just,
I'm not even a fan of clips
as, as a way of discovery
clip for me is the best
use of clips is something
that you share on Twitter.
I don't use Facebook, but you know,
and I think Instagram is tough.
It's like, here's, here's
this fantastic clip.
It's a minute.
It's two minutes.
It's five minutes, whatever it is.
It has a beginning, it has an ending, uh,
as a way for you to get
to the original and
it, and it's easy to share.
That's, that's the, that's
the utility of a clip for me.
And in fact, that is
what the Rogan show uses
by design is when he
put his deal together.
Uh, he, uh, stopped his, uh, work with
YouTube and connected Spotify and YouTube.
And those guys worked out a money deal
as to how much YouTube could share,
how many minutes, et cetera.
Oh, that's how that thing came about.
Yes.
So now it's, uh, I think it's
Jamie who still selects the clips.
Um, and that's a, and
that's really important
because that's where a lot
of comments take place.
That's where people
talk about other clips.
They post links to stuff that's
discovery in, in this realm.
You know, I just don't
see it being functional.
And again, with clips,
it's the same thing.
I'm just, I just don't see it.
I've never heard anyone
say, all right, no,
let me just turn it around for
the past two and a half years.
How have people discovered
the no agenda show?
There's one way.
It's the top.
It's from Joe Rogan.
Yeah.
And number two is, uh,
from, um, Tom Woods.
And in fact, we have, uh, little
acronyms like, Hey, I'm a,
I'm a Ronimo listener, which
means you came from Rogan
to no agenda to mo facts.
You see that, that, okay.
But here's, here's the issue though.
That leads people to believe that
because, because that's actually,
that's absolutely true.
You went on Rogan and you went on Tom
Woods and you went on Megan Kelly.
It's called marketing.
Right.
And you went on those shows and you
brought cause there was essentially,
I mean, because
you were there and you were talking and,
and that brought people back to your show.
So that, that fact leads people
to believe that you could,
that you can automate that in
a way that says, I'm going to put you
on, I want to have myself on your show,
but not actually have to be a guest.
Right.
Okay.
So that's where I say, no,
that just doesn't work.
I mean, of course you're going to have
a percentage of stuff that works,
but no, the, the, I mean,
that's, that's the way it's done.
And, and of course not every show is
appropriate to have a guest, you know, but,
uh, no agenda has, I mean, look
at, look at no agenda stream.
This is the best podcast network in the
world because it's not a podcast network.
It's just a chat room.
Thank you.
Void zero has been there for 13, 14 years.
Um, uh, a chat room that has a,
that has live podcasts and recorded
podcasts and, and it, and it pops up.
Oh, this is playing right now.
Oh, okay.
That's good.
And, uh, there's a feedback loop, man.
The way people discovered no
agenda was through John C.
Dvorak shilling it on this
week in tech every Sunday.
That's how it works.
It's called marketing.
Yeah.
This, this is the fallacy
of the so-called industry
as with other so-called industries.
Big tech will just make it all work.
Yeah.
YouTube does that.
YouTube also owns everything and you
and you have no control over shit.
You know, and well, I
can game the algorithm.
No, you can't.
Cause they'll just change it.
Well, see the, I'm not, I guess I'll
push back a little bit because it not,
not really because I, I, I don't
really believe in this a whole lot.
What I'm with the, this,
this whole automated thing,
but it feels like you got, okay.
You've got program, you
have programmable money.
Mm-hmm.
And so there must be a way automate
the money aspect of it in a sense.
Now, please understand that I do not
believe for one second that, uh,
like DAI buying ads on another page.
I've never once listened
to another show because
I heard it advertised on a
show I was listening to.
Not once.
And I've, I've heard it
hundreds and hundreds of times.
I don't necessarily believe
that's the way it works,
but partly it could be that the reason
that doesn't work as it's, as it, as it is
done today is because it's the podcasters
themselves that are building and creating
the clip to share somewhere else.
Okay.
So if you had like the, this
probably is true for Rogan as well.
I mean, when you, when the podcaster
themselves creates the clip, it's not,
it's never the thing that everybody wants.
It's when the things that go viral,
like you're talking about sharing a clip
on Twitter, those are always, okay.
Good example.
The thing that went viral this, you
know, over the last couple of days was,
um, George
Bush flubbing and saying, saying Iraq
instead of, uh, Ukraine, uh, in that clip.
Well, well, if he, if his people had
chosen the clip to share from that,
from that talk, that would
have obviously not been it.
It's correct.
It's, it's, it's always some
other piece of the show.
And so if you turn that clippage over
to, over to the, the, the crowd,
so to speak, and they
begin to make good clips.
Well, there's, there's your,
that's, that's the rub.
There are very few people
who can make good clips.
The, the, uh, in fact,
many of the quote unquote good
clips you see on online are good
clips because they're propaganda because
professionals went in there and clipped it.
It's particularly the ending.
I know this cause I've been,
I've been screwed many times.
Like listen to this crap.
You won't believe what this person said.
And then if you go watch the
full clip, oh, hold on a second.
That was a bit out of context or it
cut off just at the right moment.
So creating clips that
go viral is a skill and,
and most people don't have the skill.
The George Bush, the reason,
I mean, you're saying, yeah,
if someone was creating their
own clips, then they would have, uh, and
it was on the George Bush, you know,
team, they wouldn't have pulled that clip.
Well, then no one would have watched it.
It wouldn't have gone viral.
You know, it's because it's because it's
a flub because it's the best moment.
Um, John and I spend the most amount of
time post no agenda, post production.
Let me give you the sequence.
It ends during the end of show clips.
I'm already doing, I'm copy pasting.
Uh, I've been doing this for way too long.
Copy pasting from the spreadsheet
into the producer, uh, credits.
Um, the minute the show stops,
I have marked and I mark on the
fly while I'm doing the show
four or five, sometimes 10 different
spots, uh, with either an edit,
which is rare, you know, if
it's the feed drop or whatever,
or something that was said
that could be a good opening.
No agenda show always starts
with an opening thing,
which is our version of a clip that
we, oh, okay, there's something
funny coming or, oh, that's crazy.
Where is that?
Um, so we go back and we
listen to them and first
I got to select them and then it's, you
know, it's eight or nine of these
and okay, blah, blah, blah,
then I got to trim them
down and John is, you know, he's pooping.
He comes back and they're like, okay, uh,
then we listen to them, then we select it.
It takes time and we,
and we discuss which one it's going
to be because it's, it's a skill.
You can learn it, but,
but creating a good clip that is going
to entice people to listen is a skill.
It's not to be automated and
it's not for most people.
In my opinion, it's just, you
just don't get great success.
Obviously, if there's
something hilarious, flub,
funny that everyone can recognize, that's
something great that you
want to be able to clip,
but it's not something you can count on.
Yeah.
I'm not passionate enough about it
to argue, to make a big argument.
We like programmable money.
That's the thing.
I think we're enamored by how many more
ways can we automate some payment?
I mean, that's, that's
what has me all jacked up.
So I kind of get that.
That's exactly it.
I want, like, once you
see that you can do that,
then you just want to
do it for everything.
Oh yeah.
No, I set up my own LNURL pay server.
You know, I got it.
You can, you can, you
can send me LNURL pays.
I've been trying to create adamatkurry.com
as my lightning payment address.
And of course, all of these
things are super exciting.
The great thing is, is that this
is all dribbling away from us.
You know, I, we, we had a channel close and,
uh, an out of sync wallet this morning.
Uh, so payments weren't
going through to MoFax
and I couldn't open a
channel from Podcast Index.
And, you know, I had, uh, the
dog trainer for our last dog.
We, we graduated by the way.
Uh, congratulations.
Thank you.
You could hear the dog,
how well trained she is.
She's, uh, she listens
perfectly to me now.
Yeah.
She's clearly a graduate.
She's a graduate.
Uh, and, um, uh, you know.
So it was stressful.
I'm like, man, we're, we're, we're,
we shouldn't have to be doing
this channel stuff anymore.
You know, that's what I want breeze
to manage or voltage to manage.
You know, these, these should be things
that are not even an issue for us anymore.
And they will be, that's where it's going.
But, you know, we're, we're,
we're super hobbyists.
I mean, come on.
I got two umbrellas running here.
I'm, I'm, I'm running IPFS.
I mean, this is nuts.
I'm running with scissors.
Yeah.
This is, this is who we are.
I mean, I'm already thinking, how
can I, here's, here's the puzzle.
If someone is running an umbral and is
pinning, uh, my episodes, I want them,
I want them to get a split.
This is the next step.
That's the thing I'm
interested in on IPFS.
Right.
I wish that I, I wish I had
more confidence in IPFS.
I mean, I've, for clarity,
we've been specifically,
me and you have been doing
IPFS in some capacity.
Oh, for almost a decade.
Oh my God.
Almost a decade.
Yeah.
It's been forever.
And, and I just wish I've seen it
fall down so much so much that I,
like even recently,
I thought when we put up the database
for full, for download over IPFS,
I thought, okay, this has
been, it's been a few years.
It'll all work.
Yeah.
And I'm going to, and I'm going to put
it through the Cloudflare gateway.
Yeah.
Those guys are, you know, those
guys know what they're doing.
You know, they're smartest
guys in the room.
It's all going to, this
is going to be fine.
No, no, no, at least once a week I was
getting, Hey, the feed won't download.
And so I just ended up doing
it on HTTPS and, or HTTP.
I don't know.
It, it, I want to be proven wrong
about this because I, I mean,
it would be beautiful if it worked.
The other thing that
bothers me a little bit
about IPFS is their infatuation
with the file coin thing.
Yeah.
That, that part, I don't like at all.
That's shit coinery.
It's shit coinery.
Yeah.
We don't need that.
And, you know, going back.
Do you remember we read that,
we talked about that thing,
the Patreon study about, was it
40% of podcasters don't want crypto?
Mm-hmm.
And, you know, that, that
really wasn't, wasn't actually.
That wasn't the Patreon study.
That was the Podlands, the Podnews study.
No, no, no, no.
This was Patreon.
No, I've got.
Oh, no, I'm sorry.
Yes.
I know what you're talking about.
Yeah.
Exactly.
Well, you know, I, I was reading
more on, on that and, uh, you know,
we talked about, well, they, you
know, how did they actually get,
when they asked the podcasters or the,
you know, quote unquote
creators, how much, uh,
like how interested are
you in crypto currency?
What they really asked them was like, do
you want NFTs and all this kind of stuff?
Right.
And one of the things was like, uh, they
talked about a Patreon coin, you know, I'm
like, I mean, that's, that's different
than just not wanting crypto.
That's not wanting a bunch of
shenanigans is what that is.
Well, I think that, you know,
there's a lot going on right now.
I mean, we're seeing the total
meltdown of the shit coin marketplace.
There's something really wrong in the
financial system right now, by the way.
I'm not sure what it is, who it is.
Someone is sick.
Could be a bank.
God forbid.
It could be, it could be a bank.
It could be Goldman Sachs for all I know.
But, uh, but with this,
uh, uh, you, with the, um,
the Luna coin and all this stuff, what
happened there, there's
sickness in the system.
So people are now starting
to understand, uh,
the difference between crypto and Bitcoin.
It's, it's still going to take many,
many years for people, for every,
for the majority of people to
see it and to understand it.
And every day there's another crypto coin
coming on the market, doing something.
John and I were solicited by, I think
it was the outfit that, that, uh,
hot news reported
on in a appropriately, um, uh,
skeptical way or kind of cynical way,
which was the guys
who were paying podcasters to
onboard listeners into their system.
Oh yeah.
The, uh, we're going to, you're going to
get a million dollars of free money guys.
Yeah.
Those guys, let me see.
A thousand dollars per thousand listeners.
Rock, rock fin, rock fin, R-O-K-F-I-N.
So what rock fin does in, uh,
in essence is they pay you for
onboarding system people into,
uh, their monetization system,
which as far as I can tell is
another shit coin, which they
kind of hide in the back end.
So they're going to pay you in these.
It's basically, it's like an ICO, all of
these things, they all wind up blowing up.
I mean, the ICOs blew up.
Then we had the, uh, NFTs.
I think those are over now.
NFTs are done.
You know, it's like the
market has collapsed.
Uh, and then now everyone's looking
at DeFi, which is this, you know,
really a huge connected,
I don't want to say Ponzi scheme,
but connected scheme of, well,
this stable coin is backed
by this, uh, alt coin, which is ultimately
backed by Bitcoin and some other,
you know, paper, that all sounds fine.
That's all good.
Sounds perfect.
Um, I can't, but you know, what
I'm waiting on, this is a bigger,
this is a bigger topic
because I talked to, uh, Alex,
uh, every now and then, uh,
on the signals and he's into, um,
he's enamored with, uh,
Monero at this point.
So we, we talk about Monero every,
every now and then he sends me, uh,
information about it.
And it's, uh, the, the tech
of, of Monero is cool.
And I've never, I've, I knew of it.
Um, if you know Monero about,
if you know of it through just
sort of secondhand information,
what you know is that, that it's like the
shadowy dark, you know, money crypto.
So, oh yeah, well this, this is, um, Void
Zero was all into that a while back.
I don't know if he still is, but he
was like, hey man, Bitcoin's great,
but Monero, that's where it is.
Monero and Solano.
Now I don't know anything about Solano.
I know Monero, Monero.
They both sound like Italian
salad dressings to me.
I'm not sure why that is.
Yes, yes.
Uh, yeah, I would like, uh, Monero
and cucumbers on the side, please.
Um, with, with little Solano on top.
Solano, yes.
Uh, the, and a, uh, a
vintage, uh, 1974 Cardano.
The, the, what, you know, the, the thing
about Monero is that it's got a bunch,
it was built from the very beginning.
This is not an ad for Monero,
but, um, the thing about it is,
is it was built from the
ground up to be like
completely private and it's
got some pretty cool stuff in there about
like, uh, X, uh, extendable block sizes
and that kind of thing to go up and down.
And then you, but if the blocks
get too big, you get penalized.
It's like this adaptive block size thing.
It's a lot of cool tech.
What, you know, what I was telling
Alex the other day is that, you know,
the tech, you've
got the tech side of it and then
you've got the political side of it.
And then what I'm a,
so something like Monero seems like
a thing that is technically sound,
like from a technology
standpoint, it's, it's solid.
And, and you can sort of like not,
you can't find really a fault with,
with the technology of it, but
I'm afraid that a thing like that
ultimately gets wrapped up and
destroyed by the shit cornery.
And so that you, you had a possibility to
have something that could operate, uh,
as a, as an alternative, because
I don't envision a future.
I envision, here's, here's the future.
I envision, and I envision
a future where Bitcoin
is legitimized within the financial
system to the point where
it's just a, a de facto.
I think we're almost there.
Honestly, it's a fact of a lot.
Yeah.
It's like, okay, this is a thing that's
going to exist and it's going to be used.
And that's just, that's just
going to be how it is then.
But that doesn't mean that every other
cryptocurrency is without any utility at all.
Because, I mean, we've already
seen that look at hive.
I mean, hive has, has
utility, it has utility.
I agree.
And so you have, you have
cryptocurrency that is,
whose primary function is monetary.
And to me, that is, there is only one
that is Bitcoin currently the, the,
then you have other cryptocurrencies
that serve a function.
They have a, they have a utility to them.
And, um, so I would, and
I would classify that.
I would classify hive as one of those,
um, Monero's function is privacy.
And it can, these things can
still operate as a currency.
They're just not the default currency.
Like, I mean, if, if, if the
petrodollar, if the dollar is,
is the primary world reserve
currency, and we think of that sort
of like as a, as a Bitcoin analogy,
well then, you know,
maybe Monero is, uh, you know,
the Deutschmark or something.
I mean, like having, having utility with,
with volatility and price is complicated.
Uh, to me, it can only really
start to qualify as a currency.
If it's proof of work based, if it's
proof of stake based, then no, I mean,
it can be a great utility,
but there's a lot,
you have literal stakeholders
who make decisions.
And yeah, I know, please, I don't
need the post, Brian, that, you know,
hive and everyone did it good.
And there's all these
rules and it can't happen.
And there's delays and
three days and 47 hours.
And I understand, but to me,
it's proof of work is the only
thing that would even come
near to be, to being able
to be called a currency.
Everything else is a utility
and a utility can go away.
I mean, when, when this Luna thing
happened, I looked at, cause you know,
hive has a similar structure.
Again, we don't need to
have a discussion about
it cause it's just tiring and I don't
know enough about it.
But from a layman's
perspective, it's very similar.
You have HBD and you have hive and one,
and one backs the other and
there's a price and that,
you know, and that price
has volatility and they
have a lot of safeguards so that it really
can't function, um, like a
currency, like, like Bitcoin would.
It's also proof of stake based.
So I don't know.
I mean, you can say that
stable coins are currency.
The problem is what's backing it.
If it's stake, proof of
stake, then that can go away.
If it's proof of work, well, then it's
only as good as the network that is,
that is creating the proof of work.
And see, that's where Monero
is, is proof of work.
And, and that's what I'm saying.
If you get into, if you get what you
take a, a technically sound blockchain,
uh, crypto
Bitcoin like Monero and you say, okay,
this, this thing is, is well-built.
It's, it's really functional.
Now you have to start
asking other questions.
Does it have volume?
Does it have buy-in?
Does it have, uh, you
know, what, what are,
now you start to layer
the political questions
on top of it and ask.
And in that process, you see,
that's where I lose confidence.
I don't lose confidence in the
technology of something like Monero.
I lose confidence in its abilities to serve,
to survive government and, and market.
How about just, how about
just forget government?
Let's just look at market functionality.
I'll give you a perfect example.
For, uh, a couple of months,
everybody was all jacked.
Oh, I've got the crypto
name, uh, domain name.
I got the domain name, handshake, the
HNS domain name, got the domain name.
Everybody fell for it.
And guys who were like Dave.eth
or something like that.
Yes.
Well, no, H, the HNS, um, HNS,
that's the handshake name.
Oh, the handshake that, yeah,
I gotcha, I gotcha, yeah.
You know, it's like, oh, and, and so
I, I've been following the television
Telegram group since that day.
And what, since the day I said, no,
I'm sorry, I don't need your HNS
because you're basically selling
me some kind of shit coin.
Uh, you're giving it to me, which is
kind, but a shit coin that I can't use.
It doesn't actually work with
the, with the DNS system.
There's no way.
Yeah.
If I run my private DNS server,
but I don't need you for that.
Um, and so I followed this thing
and it's all about the price.
I don't give a shit about domain names.
No one's hooking this up
to their domain name.
It's a coin.
They're trying to get the price up
and it's not, not doing very well.
Yeah.
I guess I just hate seeing that there's,
when there's things that are technically
so well designed that they don't, they
get, they get sidelined by other problems.
And I mean, that's, this is nothing new.
I mean, it's not unique to the Bitcoin.
I mean, to the, to the cryptocurrency
world, but like, well, I mean, I,
I keep in the
chances by that line of reasoning is
the U S dollar actually a currency.
No thing.
That's exactly what I'm talking about.
But the U S dollar is backed by, uh,
a $750 billion a year
military that says you will
use our shit coin, our fun, our fiat fund
coupon, the U S dollar, or let me see.
Oh, you want to sell your
oil for a gold dinar?
What's your name?
Gaddafi?
Oh, I'm sorry.
We're coming to kill you.
Yeah.
We came, we saw he died.
What's your name?
Oh, you're Saddam Hussein.
What do you want to do?
What did you want to do with the oil?
No, we're going to, it's
not in the U S dollar.
You want euros?
Russia?
Russia has always wanted to sell,
uh, oil in, in, in other currencies,
their own, for example.
Look at that.
And I just, there's a, there's the
larger discussion here of this.
So I go back on the Bitcoin side.
I go back to this, this sort of Darwinian
dilemma that I have with Bitcoin also.
And I tried to talk about this a
little bit with Gigi, um, is there,
there was this idea.
I forgot who said it, but it was like, if
you get to the presidency, like if you,
if you make it through and you become
the president of the United States, um,
you have to have been
corrupted at some point.
Uh, so you take a guy,
the only person that I've ever
even considered voting for in the
last 20 years of, of
elections is Ron Paul.
But then I, but then I kept
telling myself, you know, if,
if Ron Paul actually got elected
as president, that means
he probably would have
had to compromise himself in some way.
And therefore I wouldn't, I
wouldn't want him either.
Like in order to get to the top, you,
you almost by default have to
be compromised in some way.
And so you can, you can, you can
advocate for a, for a thing,
but the thing that you're
advocating for by necessity, if it
attains what you want it to attain,
it's not what you wanted it to be anymore.
And so the same thing
with Bitcoin, I wonder,
and I'm concerned if
Bitcoin ultimately makes
it to be the thing that we sort of want
it to be, which is the default currency,
you know, if world, the
world currency at what,
how did it have to be molested in
order for it to attain that status?
Well, it won't.
And is that, is that KYC?
No, it won't.
It's, to me, all of that
is irrelevant to me.
Um, now where, where is
the, so first of all,
the distinction for me
is Bitcoin is, it's,
it's resistant to all of that.
It's resistant to, to all, all
the issues that we have with,
with any proof of, well,
any other coin basically.
And there's, there's now,
uh, 13 years to show.
So, uh, it's, it's working.
Um, the, as much regular,
banning bit, the use of Bitcoin,
banning it is as futile as banning
email from a technical level.
Now, exchanging your money into Bitcoin
and vice versa is a different issue.
So, if you, if anyone
thinks that that's going to
be easy and that this
integration of Bitcoin,
uh, uh, legally and easily
into the financial system, no,
that's not going to be easy.
It's not, it's never going to be easy.
It's, and they don't want
any of it, any of it.
They want their own system.
So, the only way to go is to just use it.
Now, if Bitcoin goes to $1,
I think it's still great to use
amongst, amongst each other.
You know, for exchanging,
there's been versions of,
of money throughout our
history, throughout the U.S.
history, you can get Texas dollars, you
know, Texas had multiple types of dollars.
All of this is, and it's completely legal
to do, you know, but we're up against,
uh, uh, maniacal nutjobs who are trying to
desperately hang onto a system that is,
uh, imploding.
Yeah, and that's, that's kind of what
I'm getting at is, is, uh, I think, I'm,
I think we're not far apart because
we're, there's the technical,
the technicals of Bitcoin
are, are, they're set.
I mean, you can't, it doesn't matter
what the government would want to do,
they can't be changed.
What can be, you know, modified or molested
or, or, or corrupted, if you want to,
if you want to say that is,
is all the things around it.
How do you, how do you get it into, you
know, when it goes into an account, uh,
an exchange or when it
comes out or, or, you know,
we're going to put you in
jail if you don't 1099
everybody that you send a payment to.
Yeah, I know you're hung up on this.
I am.
I am hung up on it because
like, that's, that's a,
that's a way that the thing can be, well,
you know, oh, well, you
don't want to 1099.
Well, just let our chain analysis
guys hook into your node.
Um, those sorts of things can, can,
and there's, there's already, right.
But, but, but, but bear with me, none of
that stopped, stopped the use of Bitcoin.
None of it.
Bitcoin.
So what, what you're saying is Bitcoin
can be used, but we'll have, it can't be,
uh, anonymous if you want to cash out or,
or, you know, if you, if you want to use,
if you want to use an exchange.
Now, if I just want to go get some
money, some Bitcoin for some, uh,
for some paper dollars,
uh, there are decentralized exchanges.
There's a lot.
You can go to the coffee shop.
There's a lot of ways to do that.
Now, luckily we don't have to do that
at this, at this moment in time,
but I'm KYC'd where I buy my Bitcoin.
Is that a problem?
Well, the only problem has
nothing to do with Bitcoin.
If we need to KYC, if we need to
1099 everybody who sends a donation,
no agenda is just as fucked
with PayPal as it is with Bitcoin.
The only difference is I already know
who everybody is thanks to PayPal.
So I can say to the IRS,
well, here's your list.
Here's the list.
I don't.
But if they said, oh, you've got a 1099.
So, okay, well, just
1099, all these people,
I got an email address
and I'll send it to them.
And, uh, there you go.
Um, so would that have
to, it would be sad.
It would be sad if I had to do that
for cash donors, PayPal donors,
or Bitcoin donors, but
it's not stopping Bitcoin.
No, I don't think it is stopping Bitcoin.
And that's kind of the problem.
Um, and, and I'm not, I'm
probably not describing,
I'm probably not doing
good with my word choices,
but that's, you're right.
I am hung up on the 1099
thing because what bothers
me is that there's not
been movement on it.
Now I think that there's
plenty, there's still,
there's still time to
have movement on that
thing to get that regulation
reworded by the end of the year.
But I mean, that thing goes into,
goes into effect January 1st, 23.
And so the, if, if it doesn't get
changed, that's a problem to,
that's a problem to, to
me, it signals that the Bitcoin,
Bitcoin as an ecosystem and
industry decided that they
were very, that they're
comfortable with the, uh,
with sort of the small players and the,
and the grant, the play up nets of the
world just being wiped out of the game.
But let's, let's, but I don't know if you,
if we're talking about
the 1099 issue as the
same thing, the 1099
issue is a 1099 issue,
regardless of what payment system you use.
That will, but, but see, but you, but
you identified it with the PayPal thing.
When it comes through
PayPal, everybody's KYC'd.
If our lightning node forwards a
payment, collect an aggregate,
in aggregate, forwards $600 worth
of payments in a year to somebody
else, we can't know who it is.
But hold on.
A 1099 is for money you've paid to a
freelance worker or independent contractor.
These are gifts and donations.
They're not tax deductible, but I have no,
so this is where it becomes
interesting and perhaps an issue.
Um, Dreb Scott.
Now, Dreb Scott, uh,
gets an automatic split from every
payment from every podcast that I
do because he's doing the chapters.
Now, I, I have no deal with him.
I haven't asked him to do that.
I have no contract.
Um, I, it's an arbitrary amount that I've
assigned to him and I don't pay him.
I'm not paying him.
He's getting a split of a donation.
So, is he now an independent
contractor to the person listening?
No, no, that, you're, you're
misunderstanding me because we, you know,
this is the conversation
we had with Eric and I'm on your, and I'm,
I'm on your way of thinking with this.
No, no, he's, that, I
think all of that is fine.
That's, that's, you know, from,
from that standpoint is fine.
I'm specifically talking about
the bipartisan infrastructure
bill requirements that require,
um, transactions between two wallets
that have a fair market value of,
of $600 or more.
Those things have to be reported.
They're now reportable.
That, that specific language
in that bill is the
one that everybody
freaked out about because
it would just kind of destroy lighting.
It would destroy everything.
Again, so the, so there it was
for brokers, if I'm not mistaken.
Brokers, yes.
Brokers.
The definition of brokers was so broad.
I'm reading it, I'm reading it here.
Uh, beginning 2023 tax year,
this is for cryptocurrency exchanges
or brokers will be required to collect
taxpayer identifying information.
We're not a broker.
I'm not a broker.
You're not a broker.
I'm not an exchange.
But the language around what qualifies as
a broker was so vague that that's what the
problem was, was that everybody,
even developers running a Bitcoin node
at home could be considered a broker.
The infrastructure bill
redefines the term broker
to include any person
who for consideration
is responsible for regularly
providing any service,
effectuating transfers of digital
assets on behalf of another person.
That's a, that's a, that's
a, that's a routing node.
See that, that could be, it could,
it could be, yes, you're right.
Under the infrastructure bill,
cryptocurrency exchanges will be treated
similar to traditional brokerage houses.
The infrastructure bill
doesn't specifically
identify the type of information returned.
It must be filled, blah, blah, blah.
So let's, let's, let's, this is
what I do for a living actually.
So let's look at IRC 6045.
I'm kind of good at this.
IRC 6045.
Here we go.
US code.
And that, and this is current, I believe.
Every person required to make a
return on the furniture, okay.
The name, address, phone number,
and the information, okay.
Let's see.
Broker.
If, uh, transfer securities of a
customer for use in a short sale,
receives on behalf of
a customer, a dividend,
tax exempt interest.
No, um, I don't know, Dave, you know,
but I mean, bottom line, of course,
they can legislate all
kinds of crazy shit.
Now, will this happen in practice?
I don't know.
I don't, I, but I also
don't live that way.
That's just me.
I'm just balls to the wall.
I've always been to pirate and
we'll see where the chips land.
Uh, there's enough people who have
way more at stake than we do in, uh,
in how this will work, if,
if, if it can work at all.
So, I mean, I understand where one
could say the lightning network is,
facilitates a transaction.
Yeah.
I, I, I can understand that.
Um, I, I don't know.
I just don't see it happening that way.
Uh, I, I think the, the,
the bigger problem is not lightning
network, but it's on chain.
I just lost, here you go.
You're back.
Connected.
I don't hear you.
All right.
Dave's computer.
That's locked up.
Let me see.
Was that Linux?
So that's your Linux box that crashed?
Is that what happened?
Can you hear me now?
Yeah, I hear you.
But was that your Linux
machine that crashed?
Uh, yeah, it was, it just froze.
Yeah, totally.
I was right in the middle of
talking and it totally froze.
Is it on, uh, what are
you, what are you running?
Me, uh, Ubuntu?
Ubuntu, yeah.
I have, yeah.
I was running a boot.
Did your software, um,
update thing pop up?
Uh, if it did, it popped up behind
everything else because I didn't see it.
Because I found that if
you have Firefox open and
then all of a sudden the software updater
pops, then your machine,
my machine freezes.
I had Brave open.
It could have happened.
Could have happened.
I don't know.
Anyway, what I, what I was saying
is, I really don't know, Dave.
I mean, uh, I, I just don't
live in fear that way.
I understand.
I'm not saying you're living in fear,
but I, I've been a pirate all my life.
I just like, I just move forward
and we'll see what happens.
And usually it works out.
And this, I don't know, it's going to
be, it's going to be a massive fight.
If the lightning network is
in jeopardy, I don't know.
You know, what am I, I
don't know what to say.
Yeah, I mean, it doesn't really bother
me that much, you know, at the moment.
I mean, if, if something,
you know, if they don't,
I guess I'm just bringing it up because
if they don't, there's,
there's the broader, yeah,
there's just the broader question here
of, of, of all these,
what the regulations mean if
certain things do or do not happen.
And I'm, you know, it,
like I said, it doesn't,
it doesn't bother me at
this point, but there's
going to be what I see.
I'm a, you take something like Monero.
I think that thing's just going to be
swept into, into a regulatory doom.
You know, it's like, yeah, okay.
It's technically a good, a good product,
but it's just going to, I feel,
I feel like it's
just going to be like thrown away because
I mean, it just can't be allowed to exist.
Something that's whose whole
purpose is to obscure payment data.
I mean, that's just, they're
not going to let that happen.
And then, but then with the big, with
Bitcoin, the broader, the, you know,
a lot more long-term
question is, uh, is it, is
it going to be corrupted?
And I just don't know the answer to that.
And that, that most pressing, you
know, regulatory, regulatory speaking,
is it going to be corrupted?
And I just don't know.
Well, so the, so back to your
analogy, um, where, you know,
a politician almost has to
get corrupted to get to the top.
Maybe, um, uh, Bitcoin is uncorruptible.
The, the, it's a protocol, you know,
it's like, is email corruptible?
No.
Does, does email get fucked?
Yeah, of course.
People do all kinds of
crazy shit, but it's,
it's still email still
is email and Bitcoin
will just be Bitcoin
and it will still work.
And the lightning network will
be the lightning network.
Um, I'm okay with the system as it,
like the current system of like,
if I have to give
my bank a, you know, driver's license or
something like that, I mean, it's not,
I'm, I'm okay with that.
It's not like it's the end of the world
and I'm just, it's just horrible.
I do it every day.
I mean, with, that's how we interact with
the financial system and it doesn't,
it doesn't bother me that much because
I don't, I don't do shady stuff,
but at the same time, like
I, I guess, okay, here, here's,
maybe here's my, here's a,
here's an aspect to this, not
to belabor the point, but the,
what we've been told about
Bitcoin is that it was resistant
to some things that it's not
actually resistant to such as,
such as the privacy thing.
Well, I, I disagree.
I've never heard that, that
it was, that it was private.
Um, well, I mean, I have, I mean,
people have sold it that way.
Yeah.
Well, that, that, that's a, that's bad.
That's a misnomer.
It's, it's not, Bitcoin transactions
are inherently completely public.
And the only way you can have some privacy,
I believe is mining your own Bitcoin.
And even then there's a trail
because, I mean, I, I use slush pool.
So there's a trail from slush pool to me,
but those sats that I have
in a separate wallet,
they're pretty clean.
No one would necessarily know
where they're coming from.
Although I think that's also traceable.
So, but that has never
been an issue to me.
That's been crystal clear.
It's like, there's no privacy.
Now, can you use it like
cash, um, to a degree?
Yes.
But you can't take your
dirty hundred dollar bills
and buy some Coke and
no one know about it.
You can't, I mean, no, that's,
and in fact, funny enough,
that's how I learned about Bitcoin
is, Oh, what's this thing?
You can buy Coke.
And I did it on the show.
I was like, cool.
I'm going to, I don't even do Coke.
Let's buy some Coke.
And I, I think I spent five Bitcoin
or something back in the day on, uh,
what was the, uh, what was that?
Uh, what was the name of
the, the, the tour website?
When it's Silk Road and Silk Road.
Yeah.
Silk Road.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, Ross Ulbricht's mom is
still trying to get him out of jail.
You know, so there was, there was
now that was also for other things.
It wasn't just that, you know, he also
hired a hit man and some other bad stuff.
There's that part of it, but no,
I never saw it as anonymous.
Now it's what I like about the lightning
network is that's pretty darn anonymous.
Yeah.
That's pretty cool.
Uh, but the, but ultimately the top
you have, you know, you have your,
your multi-sig wallet
and that's how your, your, your
chain, how you settle on chain.
And no, so, okay.
So I think we both agree that that,
that was marketed very poorly.
Really.
It was marketed that way in reverse, I
think by people like, uh, central bankers.
Saying, oh, you know, this is all
for, you know, illicit stuff.
People want Bitcoin so they can buy drugs
and, and weapons and, and, and bribery.
And no, that's, that's, it's
not appropriate for that.
Suitcases full of dollars
are still better.
And there's, you know, the, the ransomware
guys are still doing this in a,
in a way that
is evidently to some extent, if they do it
correctly, untraceable because they're,
I mean, they're getting away with it.
And so are they, are they, I
mean, they recovered some,
some idiots just had that on some exchange
and it was completely traceable.
So yeah, that's what I'm saying.
If they do it, if they do it the right
way, it's, it's still on, you know,
it's, they're doing it
untraceably somehow.
I guess I don't know if they're
using coin joins or whatever.
So that's just that,
see, that's the thing.
There's this privacy focused
section of the Bitcoin
people that I feel like are, they've
been on the privacy bandwagon
for, for a long time.
And they've, and it's, it's just losing,
it's losing that aspects of things,
the coin joins and that kind of thing.
Which, because it makes no sense.
I mean, it's an open, it's an open ledger.
You can follow every
wallet to every wallet.
I just want to make money on my podcast.
If I have to pay taxes,
okay, as long as it's fair.
You know, I don't, I don't like
the way it's being treated.
I don't like it being treated as an asset.
And like, there's a lot of things.
There's also benefits to that in a
weird way from a tax perspective.
I don't like any of it, but
I just want to, you know,
pay for stuff and get paid in a
money that I trust more than, so I want
to give money to truckers, you know,
or I want to give money, you know, I,
you can't do it through GoFundMe anymore
because that shit gets shut down.
It's not safe.
Yeah.
This is what I, this is what
I said at Bitcoin 2022, 2022.
I said, back in the day, in the
MTV, you know, music business days,
you bought a Rolex and
said, I got fuck you money.
Look at my Rolex.
These days I can send you
money and no one can stop it.
That's fuck you money.
That's the difference.
You can't stop me transferring it.
Now, can you do, if it's
illicit trade or whatever?
Yeah.
There's all kinds of rules
that you can't break,
but it's still my money and I'm sending
it to someone else and making it theirs.
That's the, okay.
So that's a good point.
That's where I think it's important
to, to insert the idea that you,
in order to have
that, you say, okay, this is money that I
can send to you and nobody can stop me.
Asterisks.
As long as you've done it correctly.
Well, of course.
Yeah.
Don't.
Cause that, I think that, well,
it's of course for us though.
It's for us.
It's of course for other people,
it may not be of course,
because that what we're, what,
what I envision in my head when I
say that is you have an umbral,
I have an umbral and
I send you money that can't be stopped.
What other people have
in their head is, oh,
I've got my money on
Coinbase and I'm sending
you some money on coin on cash app.
Right.
That can be stopped.
So if it's a podcaster like a, like
the Jensen, you know, Joe, I mean,
like it has been de-platformed
and they're concerned about that.
It probably needs to be in the discussion.
And I'm sure, you know, is, is
that, Hey, in order to be truly,
in order to be truly de-platformable,
un-platform, de-platformable, whatever
the hell that word's called, in order,
in order to be truly resilient to that,
you got to go, you got to go all the way.
You got to go to private, you got
to go your own keys, your own,
your own hardware that
you got to go all the way.
You can't just, oh, I'm on cash app.
I'm, I'm good now.
That's, that's, that's education.
That's education.
And that's the hardest part.
I think it's very difficult
for people to understand.
And people also don't like that.
People want to help desk.
When I say, Hey, this
is a, your own wallet.
These are your keys.
If you lose these keys, it's done.
You're fucked.
You're not getting it back.
It's over.
Oh, who do I call?
No, it's not how it works.
Most people aren't ready
for freedom, Dave.
Freedom takes extra steps.
It does.
So does sovereign feeds.
Sovereign feeds is tougher than freedom.
That's the new t-shirt.
Sovereign feeds, tougher than freedom.
So along with all that, if I
can switch topics for a moment.
Oh, please, please do.
Comes word of a new Roadcaster,
Roadcaster Pro Mark II or something of,
this has been leaked information.
Apparently it's coming out within a week.
I am once again, kind of semi-excited.
Could they have done it right this time?
Could they have done it right?
I mean, I don't have enough
information on it yet,
but the money's burning
a hole in my pocket.
As soon as I can order
one, I'm ordering it.
Now, again, no one has called
me and asked me, oh, gee,
what is that one thing you want done?
I hope they were listening.
I've mentioned it a million times.
Don't fall for it.
Oh, I know.
It's like Lucy in the football again.
It's a lie.
It's a rugby, it's a rugby ball.
There's Australians.
I'm going to pull that ball
from out in front of me again.
I'm very excited.
I mean, it looks so close
to what I want it to be.
It looks like it has so
many of the elements.
We'll see.
I'm excited.
I mean, this is good for the show because
you, I mean, like, this is another,
this just means there's going
to be a future rant from
you about all the ways in which this thing
fell down and disappointed you.
Yeah.
Yeah, possibly.
But, you know, it's even,
there's even a slight,
this is how hopeful I am
that maybe, maybe it'll
have all the, you know, they say
they have nine configurable,
completely configurable channels
that you can route and everything.
I mean, this is just some
of the information that's
been out there and maybe it might even
work with, uh, with Linux.
I mean, it could happen.
It could happen.
It could.
I want to get rid of
this Windows box so bad.
I am so sick and tired of
what those guys are doing.
I mean, this is where I would normally
advocate for, uh, the Linux lifestyle.
But it just froze up on
me like five minutes ago.
I live the Linux lifestyle.
You know, I'm a, I'm a Linux mint guy.
That's my daily driver.
The only thing I use Windows
for is in the studio.
Uh, and I, and I'm, I'm, you know,
I've got all the bits and
bobs that just the routing
and the, and the audio just
doesn't, hasn't been quite.
And please don't email me, please don't.
You just make me mad.
You're doing it wrong.
Yeah.
It works, man.
Look, you can get this distro.
It's called the Linux audio pro.
The audio distro.
Why doesn't that exist?
It does.
Oh no, it does.
There's a ham radio distro.
There's a studio.
There's a podcasting distro.
It doesn't work.
I mean, it's not, not for what I do, but.
There's a podcasting distro?
Oh, sure there is.
Oh yeah.
Does it come pre-installed
with a cast-a-pod?
Cast-a-pod?
Cast-a-pod.
Exactly.
Um, have you, speaking of,
uh, decentralized stuff,
have you heard of this Nostr, N-O-S-T-R?
Nostr.
A truly censorship-resistant alternative
to Twitter that has a chance of working.
Yeah, right.
Yeah.
It's, uh, another one of these
things that, uh, you know,
I look at all this stuff and I
just put it in the show notes.
Maybe someone take a look at it.
I mean, it seems like it
might be something we
could use for cross-app comments, which,
where are we on that?
By the way, I see Podverse
seems to have them working.
It's done.
It's all done.
Uh, so we have two implementations.
Yeah, it's, uh, it's done.
The tag is not finalized.
It's not formalized.
It's not actually in the spec.
It's, it's still in, it's, it's
in a phase five proposal state.
Okay.
So, um, we're just, can, I want to say this
about the, about the podcast comments.
Uh, cross-app comments tag.
I'm not, I'm not renaming anything.
Okay.
We've, we've every now and then this,
this discussion crops up about renaming,
uh, the podcast, uh, about renaming
these tags from social interact to like,
you know, something else like social, but
this is where I invoke Dave Weiner's RT.
Ah, here it is.
Here it is.
Yes.
RFSM.
It totally doesn't
matter what you call it.
That is one of the main
mantras of, of, of RFSM.
And I believe in that so much.
These are, these are tags in an XML
feed that nobody will ever look at.
And it, and it's at this
point when, when it just,
there is more important things to spend
our time on than renaming these tags.
Okay.
From a purity standpoint, yes, it bothers
me that these things have weird names that
are, they're sometimes not consistent,
but I will say that 25%
of the internet runs on
PHP and PHP has the most
horribly named functions
in the standard library
of any language ever
that's ever existed.
Yeah.
It's probably true.
You know, there's the difference between,
you know, S T R I P O S, which is the name
of a function that looks for a
string inside of another string.
And right after that is S T R underscore
Lynn that gives you the links of a string.
Why does one have an underscore
and the other one doesn't?
Nobody knows.
And you know what?
Nobody cares.
And we all just know what the
names of these things are.
And it doesn't, does it
matter that the RSS, uh,
feed where all the content
lives is called the channel?
No, no, it doesn't matter.
No channel means nothing.
It's completely irrelevant term.
Well, this is, uh, this is the trap.
Thank you for ringing the bell.
I rang the bell, but thank you for
pulling the rip cord because yes,
this is where, you know, communities
devolve into bullshit for,
for weeks and months on end is
talking about shit like that.
What is not the right name?
You're right.
Yeah.
I just, it's, it's come up
a couple of times lately
and I just want to stop talking about it.
I don't care about names of things.
I love that about you.
If we're naming our project.
Yeah.
That's, I'll have an
opinion, but not tags.
So on that, where are we?
Which one?
I don't know.
Where are we with the,
well, let's do this.
And now it's time for
some hot namespace talk.
I mean, we're kind of in
the middle of it, but.
By the way, that, that Dame Jennifer
math jingle, that thing, that's,
that thing is, it's too hot to try.
No, it is.
I mean, that, you got to put that
thing back in the lockbox and took,
let's bring it out on episode 100.
Okay.
That was a mistake last time.
It's dangerous.
You can't, we can't risk it.
No, it is.
And we discussed it.
I was in South Carolina.
We did a big, no agenda meetup.
By the way, everybody at
the meetup is talking 2.0.
Hey man, I got a new app
and I'm trying them out.
And you know, there's a, there's
a lot to, it takes people.
Some, most people have never
even used the podcast app.
You'd be surprised how many
don't, don't use a podcast app.
Oh, I just listened to it here or there.
I downloaded it or, oh, two people.
People had this, two.
Two whole people.
Oh, I forgot to mention this on no agenda.
Say they, where do you
think they discovered this?
Talk about discovery.
All right.
Where did they discover no agenda?
You'll never guess.
Okay.
It's an app.
I'll, I'll, I'll, I'll lift,
I'll give you a little tip.
It's an app.
And, uh.
Is it a mo, is it a mobile app?
Uh, no, it is not a mobile app.
And, uh, Boostergrams with, uh,
guesses are also welcome right now.
Uh, anything over a
thousand sats, I will read.
Um, where, where would
they have, it's an app.
It's an app, it's an app, but
it's not, it's not a mobile app.
No, no, no.
It's an app.
It's not, it's, in fact, it is, you cannot
even get this app on mobile at all.
Oh, you can't get it on mobile.
Uh, is it, is it an open source app?
Uh, the app itself, the
code is, uh, open source.
It's published on GitHub, but
it's in a framework of a, it's a,
it's in a particular type of app store.
Napster.
No.
Roku.
Someone built a Roku app
years and years and years
ago, it's still on the Roku store and,
and literally the same, the same story.
You know, it's just looking around
and I, you know, I cut cable,
I'm looking around and
say, Oh, what is this?
There's no agenda thing.
Click.
And, and, and, and many of these people
were listening on Roku for months,
sometimes years
before they figured, Oh, this podcast, I
mean, I'll get it on an app on my phone.
That's, I would have never, I
would have never guessed that.
And no, I, neither would have I.
I mean, it's a, again, another
fantastic discovery story,
the discovery in an app itself, which
I still think is a great way.
I mean, uh, if I had a new
podcast, I do, but, uh,
if I was launching it for different
reasons, I would probably talk to, uh,
everybody at new podcast apps.com and
say, Hey, can I get some feature?
What will it cost me?
You mean nude podcast apps?
Nude podcast apps.com.
Yeah.
I'll say, can I, can I get a feature?
Let me put a split in your block, uh,
in my block to you and give me, uh,
give me some,
give me, put me on a feature on,
uh, when they open up the app.
This is when people don't know this story.
When I saw radio user land from
Dave Weiner, uh, and it was the,
really the first blogging tool.
And I had my feed, uh, on radio user land.
I, and he had a list, a
list of like the, uh,
there was a page in the app
and you, you brought it up.
It's like, here's some interesting,
um, feeds to subscribe to.
I paid him $10,000 to
always be on that list.
Oh, did you?
Mm-hmm.
What, uh, which, what feed was on it?
Uh, my, my, my blog at the time.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, that feed's long gone.
It was, it was a radio user land,
you know, uh, user land 00007.xml,
or user 7 or something.
Yeah.
So, and, and that, and
I actually remained in
that list for a long
time and it was great.
I got lots of people
subscribing to me because
it was on a recommended
list in the app that
people were using to subscribe to feeds.
That was a bit like the
friends of Twitter.
No, that's a good way to go.
But I wonder, you know,
I think, uh, who was it?
Who, who's doing, somebody told
us that they were doing, uh,
like paid recommendation.
Oh, PodLP.
Yeah.
Uh, Thomas over at PodLP.
He said like, I mean, you had like a
pricing sheet where you could do, uh,
you know, you
could pay him to get on the recommendation
page or the homepage or whatever.
I mean, it's a valid way to go for an
app for, for funding, you know, to,
to say, okay, well, I mean, absolutely
put you in the recommendation list.
I mean, that's, that's a deal.
That's a win-win.
Well, you know, now you're
talking about marketing
and now you see who's
marketing really well.
Um, I think, uh, Podverse is doing a
really good job of marketing themselves.
Uh, they have a lot of fans marketing them,
um, which is another important thing.
With the Selek podcast is, they seem to
be marketing everybody's, uh, app with,
uh, with, uh, you
know, they're always putting out little
clips and they're doing a great job of that.
Uh, Fountain is doing a
great job of marketing.
You know, it's, it's not all just
automatic and it doesn't just happen.
I always pronounce that sleek.
I thought, I, you may be right.
I don't know if it's, well, I
don't know why I said Selek.
I just think that for some reason
that's what my brain registered.
It could be wrong.
You said Selek and I thought
about a local telephone company.
Is it S, is it S-L-I-E-K?
Uh, I think so.
Yeah.
Or E-I or I-E.
One of those two.
You know, so I, I discovered something.
Sleek, you're right.
I was wrong.
Sleek.
There you go.
Sleek, yes.
Um, you know, actually we can talk about
that after we thank some people, but I,
um, yeah, we'll come back to that one.
Uh, there's been some, I've been
doing some index work and, uh,
we didn't talk about it last week.
I don't think, but, uh, there's a,
there's a few things I'm backlogged
on with the, with the index.
And, uh, one of them is the
iTunes lookup API endpoint.
So that's a, a thing that I
created to be like a, a lookalike.
It's essentially like an, like a fallback.
For the Apple, um, for Apple's API,
the one that everybody uses
where you can just look
up a podcast and get a feed URL.
Right.
Which is important for apps mainly.
Yeah.
I think, I think that could bring,
I think that would make it a
lot easier for people to use
us as a fallback because they don't
even have to change their code.
Essentially it, it, it, it, it
returns exactly what Apple returns.
Right, right, right, right, right, right.
And so basically, I mean,
literally it's identical.
All they would have to do
is go in there and change
and change the host name from, you know,
uh, iTunes at apple.com to
api.podcastindex.com and everything.
It just works.
Mm-hmm.
Um, it's, it's not fully functional yet.
I got, I still got to fill out
the categories and do that thing,
which is going to be a pain in the butt.
But that, I also have to do
category work though for
the downloads because I'm
going to, consistently
people are telling me that they wish the
categories was in the database download.
Yeah, I've seen a couple of those.
So I'm just going to do
all that at the same time.
So, so the idea is it's also
kind of like a, it's a backup,
but also a backup for onboarding.
So let's say Apple burps
and then you can just
switch one parameter in your app and then
everything is working again.
Yeah.
Like an AB, I mean, like
it's literally a fallback.
Nice.
Yeah.
I think people can use that.
I'm going to make it public.
It's not going to be, but.
Have you worked any more on your open API,
no authentication business
for the, for future scaling?
No.
Okay.
Good work.
It's the thing that I
just like to bring up
and talk a lot about and then never do it.
Never do it.
That's okay.
And I'll keep reminding you.
I just want to make sure that
we keep it on the radar.
That's all.
Yeah.
It's a, it's a perpetual non-event.
Why don't we, let's thank a couple of
people for this value for value project.
We've gone all over the map today.
Um, and, uh, I'm not sure.
Do we have a lot of people
in the, in the, in the chat?
It seems like it's a little less.
It seems like it's a little low, little,
little, little low than, uh, than normal.
And are we, way to get
like a count or something?
Uh, it's a good question.
Um, I don't, um, let me see.
Two, three, four.
Uh, I can tell you how many people
are listening to the stream.
Uh, and no, I can't.
25.
We'll get 25 in there.
Do a 25 in the chat.
Okay.
Uh, I counted it by hand cause I just had
to reboot my computer and I still see the,
uh, user list name at the top.
Uh, they have been live, uh, boosting.
Uh, so the value for value
concept is very simple.
If you get value out of this podcast and
hopefully it's not just the podcast,
but it's the entire project
is what we're moving towards.
And we'd like to see that, uh,
continue to move and to keep funded.
Uh, we need as many booster
grams as we can get.
People seem to be trans kind of,
uh, uh, transitioning from, uh,
PayPal donations to, um, uh, to Satoshi's,
which is, is fine for us, but
please know that, you know,
the numbers you see are a lot bigger
than what, uh, than what we need when
it comes down to dollars for, uh,
for paying for the servers.
However, just going through a couple here,
go podcasting from
Macintosh, a thousand sats.
Um, let me see, uh, NA millennial, uh,
5,000 sats and with a, here you go.
Uh, this is how you market your podcast.
You want some discovery.
Here's the booster gram, 5,000
sats from no agenda millennial.
Listen to millennial offensive,
the millennial media offensive.
It's better than these two nerds.
Hey, uh, Mike Newman, 211,
I'll be boost via podverse.
Obviously this opens a whole new world.
We're just taking baby steps so
far as always go podcasting,
the Floydian slips 4, 3, 2, 1
podcast for value podcast.
That is all.
Thank you.
A couple of small boosts here from
Chad F boosting from podverse.
Um, let me see, we have, uh,
this is, uh, here we go.
Um, oh, I'm already at the delimiter.
So that's comic strip blogger.
We'll do him in a moment.
Let's, uh, let's thank our people, Dave.
Uh, we got zero weekly
one-time PayPal donations.
So that's, uh, this is
what I was talking about.
Yeah.
Which is fine.
But let's, uh, let's see how we do with,
uh, with the booster grams and the boost.
Uh, we got, uh, so yeah, we
got, we got a lot of boosts.
Uh, let's see.
Uh, how many we got?
We got like 20 something boosts.
Let's, uh, Bill Prague, thousand sats.
I think Bill is a hive guy.
I think that's, I think that's
where I, where I know his name.
Okay.
Um, it says, uh, uh, let's see
if he came through pod friend.
He says a weird feels this.
I think he mistyped this.
A weird feels blockchain ignored by
most, uh, maybe you meant it's weird.
Feels blockchain ignored
by most mainstream
crypto people is changing podcast casting.
You know, Bill, just don't know
what you're trying to say there.
I'm, uh, struggling.
Let's try it again.
Let me, let me hear it one more time.
Maybe I can figure it out.
A weird feels blockchain
ignored by most mainstream
crypto people is changing podcasting.
He's talking about a hive, I think.
Okay.
Because pod ping is changing podcasting.
That's the only thing
I can discern from it.
Oh, I see.
Yeah.
That makes sense.
He's saying that a
blockchain that's ignored by
most mainstream crypto people
is changing podcasting.
There you go.
Now I've been doing this for a while.
You're an expert.
I don't know about that.
Pod, let's see.
Uh, Ron of London in the hive DAO.
162,217 sats.
Hello.
I'm rolling it out for him.
Go podcasting!
Paula.
Collar.
20 inch blades on the Impala.
Boost!
Brian, you saved, you saved the week.
You saved the week, man.
Thank you.
Uh, he says it's a catch up donation
from Brian of London and high 50 HBD.
Yeah.
Go podcasting!
It's the Luna of podcasting.
Oh, that's slow.
He's going to get mad at me now.
Yeah.
Rightly so.
Um, Kyron, Mirror Mortals podcast.
Hey, hey.
22,222 sats.
Big row of ducks.
Yo, hold on ducks.
Come on out.
Through, uh, CurioCaster.
And he says, uh, I'm wearing my Mirror
Mortals, uh, shirt, by the way,
that they sent me in the movie.
Yeah, nice shirt.
I saw it.
Beauty.
Yeah, thanks.
Mitch is awesome.
Loved this episode.
And from your reactions, you can absolutely
add me to the crew of woeful marketeers.
Uh, season one of the V4V podcast was
essentially research I did before interviewing
Adam on Mirror Mortals.
I've started listening
and, uh, I'm very excited.
I was like, I got a note from, uh,
you know, I've also been writing.
Yes, you have.
There's a lot of, there's a lot of
things that I've learned over the years,
particularly in the past,
too, with Value for Value,
that I've kind of taken for granted
because we just do it all automatically.
And now that I'm having to write it down,
it's really expanding into something good.
That's cool.
Yeah.
I mean, it's, there's so much more to it.
What was this?
I thought it was here.
It was Gigi.
What did Gigi say to me?
Gigi said, hey, Adam, love that
you're writing your Value for Value.
Value Manifesto.
It's very much needed.
If you ever need a second pair of eyes
or some feedback or even editing,
let me know.
Aw, Gigi.
Is that a boost?
No, no, that's just a Telegram message.
No, cheap ass.
Yeah, Gigi.
Don't Telegram me.
Boost me.
Boost me, bitch.
Hey, there's your t-shirt.
Yeah, OG Bit Corner.
Pony up, baby.
Yeah, come on, man.
Pony up.
Where's your value?
Where's the value in Telegram messages?
Let's see.
We got Auburn Citadel.
Oh, I hadn't heard from
Auburn Citadel in a while.
No.
49,000 sats.
Boost!
Nice.
Through Fountain, and he says, yeah, boy.
Don't just stand there.
Boost!
Yeah, boy.
Auburn Citadel again.
He says, how you doing, Booster?
How you doing, Booster?
Mm-hmm.
I think I nailed that pretty much.
Yes, and I had my finger
on the button, too.
Yeah, you didn't even need it.
I can do the jingle.
Sir Sean of the Allegheny Valley, a.k.a.
Sean McCune, 3333 sats, through
Cast-O-Matic, and he says,
boosting the distributed
free speech platform.
Ooh, nice.
Boost.
Appreciate it.
The DFSP.
Free, I started to say
defibrillated free speech platform.
That might be not far off, though.
Is this, wait, is this
another Brown of London?
What?
We have the boosts.
Mm-hmm.
Whoa, I hadn't heard that one before.
How much was the last one?
I don't remember.
The last one was 100,000.
This is 166,907.
He fat-fingered us.
Go podcasting!
Nice.
Wait a minute.
What's the message?
He says special.
It's a different message.
It's got to be a different boost.
He says special catch-up.
Baller.
Shot caller.
50 HBD.
Go podcasting.
Baller.
Shot caller.
20-inch blades on the Impala.
Go podcasting!
Nice.
Thank you, Brian.
Well, Brian is now saving
the week and a half.
Well, he spent a week on
a yacht, and so now he's-
What exactly was he doing?
Was he sailing that thing?
Is this a hobby of his?
Is this a gig?
Running coke.
Oh, there you go.
Running coke from the Bahamas.
Look, they need coke in Israel, too.
Yes, they need a lot of it.
Mitch from Podverse, our
buddy Mitch, 1,968 sass.
He says,
This is the first boost from the new
value-for-value feature in Podverse.
Nice.
Congratulations.
Live in production.
Boost.
Congratulations, Mitch.
If anyone wants to easily add
V4V support to their website,
try the new open-source webln-v4v library,
found at github.com slash
podverse slash webln-v4v.
Yeah, actually, I'm going to put
that link in the show notes.
Okay.
Here it is.
Gosh, I love Helipad.
I just did a Control-F.
Boom.
Found the boost right there.
That was his 22 set.
Hey, Mitch, how come all of the boosts
that are coming from Podverse with Albie,
how come they're so low?
I mean, I have a feeling he set
his default low or something.
It's a bug.
They don't send big enough boosts.
Okay.
He says, Thanks for having me
on the show last week, guys.
I had a blast.
Go podcasting.
Yeah, go podcasting for you too, brother.
Go podcasting!
Sir Doug gave us a boost
through Fountain, and he says,
This is how money flows into podcasting.
That's right.
That's right, Doug.
Thank you.
Boost Burry sent us a boost, the
2,968 sats through Podverse.
He says, Oh, my goodness.
Very cool and very legal, Mitch.
Go podcasting!
Very legal.
Totally legal.
Hey, by the way, the video
stream is working kind of.
It's been working for a
while now on No Agenda 2.
Are people digging it?
Yeah, I think there's like five
people watching, but yeah.
Are you digging it?
I hate looking at myself.
It's the worst thing in the universe.
So you're not digging it?
No.
Eight viewers.
For the experiment, it's perfect.
Yeah.
I mean, I wish I had Tina on.
It would look a lot better than me.
Cass Peland, 3690, through
Fountain, and he says,
Thanks for the work.
Boost!
Thank you, sir.
Moritz?
I don't think I've seen
Moritz come in before.
He says, that's 32 sats.
Womp, womp, womp.
He says, Albie test.
Okay, well, I give him a pass.
Yeah, this is Albie boost.
Boost.
It sounds like an Albie boost.
Bmozzi?
22, 22, 22, 22.
Big row of ducks through Fountain.
He says, boost the dip.
Boost the dip, indeed.
Yes, sir.
What was that?
Boost the dip and...
No, it was buy the dip and boost the drip.
Boost the drip.
That's right.
Quinton, 64 sats.
It's through Podverse, and he says,
Another boost just because I
need to test Albie back in.
We will accept all tests.
We accept all of it.
Of course we do.
Gary Arndt, our buddy from the
Everything Everywhere podcast, he says,
he sends us 8,860 sats through Podverse.
Thank you.
He says, when number go down, sats go up.
Boost, boost, boost.
That's right.
Sats go up.
Quinton, again, 640 sats.
That must be it.
That's a VGA boost, right?
640.
Oh, yes, of course.
Actually, I kept that link
in the show notes almost.
Let's see if it boosts a gram numerology.
What number was it again?
640.
If it's not a VGA boost, it should be.
It's not on there.
We have the 500 is the Indie boost, and then
we go straight to 666, the Satan boost.
So the VGA boost is 640.
We need a PR.
A PR.
Yeah.
Duly christened.
Quinton sent us 640 sats through
Podverse, and he just says, awesome.
Okay.
All right.
Boost.
Awesome for you, too.
You're awesome, Quinton.
BoostBury sent us 886 sats,
and he says, Toasting.
Okay.
Moritz coming in again with
another Albie test for 32 sats.
Thank you, Moritz.
Boomy.
640.
Maybe he's the originator of
the VGA boost from previously,
and he didn't sign his name.
Boomy sent us 640 through
Podverse, and he says,
thanks for being such an inspiration.
Oh.
That's sweet.
We do our best.
Inspired and inspired.
Chad Farrow, 8,860 sats, and he says,
Sending my first boostergram
from the Podverse website.
Yeah, well, nice.
Oh, so it does work with bigger amounts.
Okay.
Good.
Yeah.
That's an indictment of everybody
who's sent a boost so far.
Except, except, Brian.
Oh, here we go.
Common Street blogger.
Ah.
Delimiter.
Mm-hmm.
15,033 sats through Fountain.
And he says, Howdy, Dave and AC.
How are you coping with Bitcoin crash?
Who are coping just fine.
He said, You switched to
gold or fiat or what?
Boost.
No, of course not.
Zoom out, brother.
Zoom out and look at that chart again.
He says, Myself, I
diversify by buying stocks.
Anyway, listeners are invited
to listen to podcasts.
Wait a minute.
What stocks did he buy to diversify?
What, you want to lose
money in different ways?
Target.
Target, Amazon, Walmart,
Apple, Google, Twitter.
What did you buy that you're diversifying?
Peloton.
What exactly?
Any energy stocks?
I mean, I don't think,
unless you're, well,
maybe if you're buying
into BlackRock or Vanguard
or State Street, but no.
I mean, that's, it is fun to
see people show up and say,
How's that Bitcoin doing, you loser?
I don't know.
How's your 401k?
Have you looked at that?
I have looked at my 401k
and it ain't great.
No.
I can promise you that.
CSB, go all in on Rivian.
It's a great idea to do that.
Anyway, sorry.
You were reading his boosted grant.
No.
He says, Myself, I
diversify by buying stocks.
Anyway, anyways, your
listeners are invited to
listen to podcasts with
news about artificial
intelligence called AI.cooking.
No, well.
Read by Gregory William Forsyth Foreman.
Oops.
Do you know where he's from?
I believe he's from Kent.
He's from Kent.
And just type in your web browser
or any podcast app, AI.cooking.
Yo.
No, that'll work.
Every time.
It will work.
Thank you, CSB.
Much appreciated.
And I got some monthly
donors through PayPal.
Keith Gibson.
Keith Gibson has been
donating $50 a month forever.
Thank you, Keith.
Keith, you need a t-shirt, brother.
Get in touch.
Yes.
Timothy Hudgens, my buddy, $25.
Dwayne Goldie, $8.
Paul Erskine, $11.14.
David Woodfine, $3.
Thomas Sullivan Jr., $5.
Great name.
And Jeremy Gerrard's $5.
That's their monthly donation.
Okay, so we did okay,
but not great this week.
At the end of this show,
we'll be able to buy lunch.
Yeah, I hope we don't have to roll
out the sad puppy on any of this.
Oh, I'm a liberal user of the sad puppy.
I mean, fire that thing up, Dreb.
Yeah.
Stick it in there.
Yeah, sad puppy.
This is value for value.
So, again, all that we need is for you
to look deep inside your heart and say,
okay, this is worth this much
to me for what I got out of it.
Now, if it's just entertainment
and laughing, all right,
maybe we're like a Disney Plus.
Disney Plus.
Yeah, maybe that's it.
Maybe if we're helping you think
differently about the world, about media,
about free speech, about technology,
maybe we're like a cable subscription.
No, that's too much.
No one would give that much money.
What does cable cut?
These days, it's crazy, the cost of cable.
I cut cable 15 years ago, and I
have no idea what it costs now.
You really?
You have no cable at all?
I'll tell you why.
So, we cut cable when we
started homeschooling our
kids because we had –
it was a big temptation
for them to just throw on the television.
No kidding.
And at the time, HD television had
just – HDTV was just coming out.
And so, you could get –
you could just get an
over-the-air antenna
and get a lot of – all
your local stations and
that kind of thing.
So, we just – we bought an over-the-air
antenna, and then we dropped cable.
Good for you.
And it saved us, oh, God,
like over $1,000 a year.
Maybe more even.
Yeah.
And we've never had it since.
That was at least 15 years ago.
Oh, good for you.
I think that's happening more and more.
These over-the-air antennas, you know,
there's a lot of technology
those guys are doing, too.
They're doing, like, two-way digital.
They have all kinds of – you can broaden.
Yeah, yeah, they're doing nutty stuff.
Yeah, it's been a year or
two since I checked into it.
And I don't know if they're going to
really bring it to market properly.
But just getting one of
those $12 antennas you
stick against the wall and hook up to the
back of your TV is quite
amazing how well that works.
Oh, see, back when we did
it, we lived in Springville,
which is 45 minutes north of Birmingham.
It's pretty rural.
Yeah.
And what we did was – I
mean, this was so long ago.
This was maybe 2000 – oh, gosh, 2015, 16.
And so we – I'm sorry,
2005 or 2006, I mean.
Mm-hmm.
And then we – so what I did
is I got a huge antenna,
like one of those big VHF-UHF combo
things that you – With a rotor?
Yeah.
It's designed to put on a rotor.
Of course.
Nice.
Yeah, I just stuck it in the attic and
then ran coax down and it had a booster,
you know, like a signal booster.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
How you doing, booster?
Yeah, and we got – Don't
just stand there, boost!
We got so many channels, bro.
I mean, we got channels from everywhere.
Well, I used to do that back in
– oh, my God, when I was 14,
living in the Netherlands,
I had a VHF antenna also under the roof and
I would manually turn it to get the BBC.
But the thing with the BBC was they had
their audio signal on a different sideband
or a different frequency
so the television couldn't decode it.
So you only had video.
You had no audio.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, man, I did so much with
antennas back in the day.
I love it.
Someone sent me one of those mining rigs
of your – it's the – what's it called?
It's the IoT, the open
source IoT network and
it's a mesh network and you have your node
and it basically communicates over FM
but you're also mining at the same time
so that people who
provide bandwidth to the
IoT systems get a little bit of this coin.
What's that called?
I got no idea what you're talking about.
I've not heard of any of this.
FM coin?
Hey, for people watching on the stream,
you're getting a good deal today.
You just saw my ass again.
Here you go.
This is Finestra.
Finestra.
Name sounds familiar.
The Finestra miner.
Yeah.
I haven't hooked it up yet
because we went to Charleston.
But it's really cool.
I'll just show it on camera.
Here's this little mining box right here.
See, now I feel like I'm missing out.
You totally are.
And it has a little antenna
and – oh, there's a note.
What does it say?
Adam, you can use this unit in your area.
I've loved learning about the tech
and hope you get some value from it.
If you don't end up using it,
I'll pay for shipping it back.
No, I'm going to use it.
Julian sent that to me.
That's how other people
send you their unit.
Yeah, yeah.
I got his unit.
And it's – no, it's – the
whole concept is kind of cool.
I mean, it's – you know, it's the same
idea as what I would like with IPFS.
You know, people providing
bandwidth for, you know,
small Raspberry Pi type like applications
that can be dropped anywhere because
you have this mesh that – I mean,
and I look on the map, the mesh
goes out to Fredericksburg.
So, I'm hoping I can pick up some signal.
I'm seeing your stream now.
I've tuned in so I can see this thing.
Oh, there you go.
Yeah.
Hey, if you boost me,
I'll take off my pants.
All of a sudden, you're a webcam girl.
Okay.
Only fans, baby.
Only fans.
What are you talking?
I had a professor in my
short-lived college days
that would – that said – he was a physics
professor, and he said, eventually,
all the smartest people in
the world go into physics.
Oh, really?
Excuse me.
Go into astrophysics.
Every – like this – it doesn't
matter what field you're in.
And you always eventually
end up in astrophysics.
Well, it doesn't matter what version
of open-source monetary thing you do.
Eventually, you all end up with only fans.
Exactly.
We're not far from it
when you think about it.
When you think about it.
Well, thank you, everybody.
Please remember to support the project.
We do need time, talent, and treasure.
The time and talent is in
abundance, and it's so appreciated,
and so many people are
doing so much great work.
The treasure seems to be lacking
a bit, but it's the transition.
So just keep – bear in mind
when you're supporting us,
bear in mind what you're really doing.
Switch that thing to
fiat so you can see what
you – to what degree you're helping us.
Yes, we want to take your
money, ice cube soup.
We have to.
Podcastindex.org.
Go to the bottom.
There's two donation buttons, one for
your fiat fun coupons through PayPal,
and we also have an on-chain donation.
But please, check out nudepodcastapps.com.
Alternatively, newpodcastapps.com.
Grab yourself one of the apps
that does value for value.
Fill up that wallet and start
boosting the heck out of us.
We could use as much as possible.
It's really appreciated.
Hey, where's Roy?
He fell off the radar.
Yeah, he fell off the radar.
Go ahead.
He knew I was going to be questioning
Bitcoin's regulatory status.
Oh, so he's zero boost from me.
He shunned me.
Yes, he shunned me.
I had an interesting, just so you never
know how people are going to use stuff.
So I'm trying to onboard a friend of ours,
and she listens to Curry
and the Keeper, and
she says, can I just send you guys money?
No.
No, you have to do it through podcasting.
This is what, you know, people are
like, can I please send you a PayPal?
No.
This is the only way you can do it.
So we're refusing money at this
point, which is really fun.
And so she's like, okay, what do I do?
She says, I don't know Bitcoin.
Just show me how to do it.
So I think, well, I don't
want to send her through
the steps of buying Bitcoin and getting
it, you know, going through
Blue Wallet and all this.
So I say, grab Breeze.
So she grabs Breeze.
She goes through the light KYC, gets
like 100,000 sats in her wallet,
and she says, okay, I'm good to go.
And then she, so she says, okay, I
boosted you guys, and it doesn't show up.
Yeah, and I kind of forgot about it as
it was time for the show, and I'm like,
is this the, is it Helipad
not exporting right?
So I can't find it.
So I say, and she said, oh, I just
opened up the app, and it says,
did not send.
I said, well, tell me what you did.
Well, I opened it up.
I went to your podcast and
hit boost and closed the app.
Oh, no.
Well, as we know, Breeze needs a second.
Yes, yes, yes.
Breeze needs a second to flush
out and to sync the graph.
And I was like, oh, okay.
So a week went by.
Honestly, my fault.
We were traveling.
I wasn't able to get to her.
And then she hasn't used the app.
And then she opens up the
app, and the channel closed.
Because this is what Breeze does.
If you don't use the Breeze
app, it closes your channel.
Right.
And then you have to send your
on-chain to another on-chain wallet.
The whole thing became just a disaster.
No, no.
But it was because she
just wanted to send money.
She wasn't listening to
the show and the app.
She'd already heard the show.
And if I'd known that, you
know, it's just the onboarding.
It's amazing sometimes
how much you go through.
I love all the things
people run into, though.
It's amazing to see what happens,
how people use things when
you think it's so obvious.
Yeah, that's the critical
piece of the whole thing,
is you have to know – you have to see the
failures in order to know what to do.
Exactly.
I mean, if it all just works,
it may be working for reasons
that you don't understand.
And it may be working in
ways that are not ideal.
So, you need – it's like –
because I learned this from you,
from observing you for years, is
you would work around problems,
and I would never know about them.
Observing me, not actually
seeing what I'm doing.
Yeah.
And you're like – and I would ask you,
you're like, oh, yeah, it's great.
Yeah, it's great.
And then we start digging in, and I
find out, you're doing it that way?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I know.
That's absurd.
Well, so this is good.
And I think – you know,
I think I have a pretty good angle
on my studio now that I like,
that I might use more often,
now that I have this fantastic
No Agenda tube to play with.
It's kind of cool.
I need to send you what I'm seeing here,
because – let me take a
picture of my screen here.
I can take a screenshot.
Are you not seeing me?
No, no, no.
I'm seeing you, but I'm just
saying that it looks really cool,
the way this – because what we're
trying to do is Super Chat.
Oh, that's exactly what
we're trying to do.
So the next – I expect next week when we
do the show for NaTube to be working in at
least one app so that we can have the
chat and the video and everything,
and then I'm going to bring you on video.
I'm going to bring you in.
I know how to do that now.
What?
You know how to bring me in on video?
Yeah, as long as you have a webcam, you've
got a cam on your camera, don't you?
Oh, that's my side gig.
Only part.
It's okay.
I won't let everyone
see it, just for money.
Trust me.
Let me send you this screenshot.
This is close to what – I mean, all
the things are coming together.
Now we just got to continue to merge them.
Oh, that does look pretty cool.
That's three separate windows,
and now we – this is what we
were talking about earlier.
We threw everything on the floor.
Now we're just scraping
them up into piles,
and then we start to
merge the piles together.
Build sandcastles, baby.
Yeah, that's the basic idea, though.
That's exactly what we want.
I just popped it up on the big
screen so everybody can see it.
I'm now a video director at the same time.
What the hell?
You're a – man, you're a damn YouTuber.
I really despise doing
this because I see it
ruins the whole magic of audio, basically.
But for some reason, people really love
listening to stuff while watching me.
I mean, not me, but watching someone sit
there and talk into the talking stick.
But see, you got to take the
arrows for Moe because he's next.
He's the next – Moe is – this is where
we're – this is the whole point.
I think the next time we do a – not
the next time, but pretty soon.
Because, you know, it's like one week
we do the show, and then we alternate.
Then it's – then he does Moe Facts Live.
He does a live on YouTube.
So that's the one we want to move over,
or at least start simulcasting
it through Podcasting 2.0.
Simulcasting like that.
Yeah, simul – well, everyone has backups.
It's the same thing as your
namespace replacement thing.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
You know, it's like people use YouTube,
and then they have Rumble as a backup.
I want everyone to have
PeerTube or No AgendaTube,
or really Podcasting 2.0 as a backup.
Can we just say that – I don't
know what to think about
Library and Odyssey and
all that kind of stuff,
but can we just say that
that's a great tactic
to use when you're
getting into the market,
is to position yourself
as the backup for – Yeah.
Well, I think positioning
is – no one's done that.
I think it's a perfect idea.
Hey, you know, you might as
well have this open-source
alternative with money
coming in as a backup,
you know, and then watch the stats
come rolling, and people will be like,
oh, hold on a second.
Yeah, it's a great idea because you have
– I mean, YouTube is dropping people off,
and so if you come into that market
as the backup, you're – I mean,
that's a legitimate thing.
Dave Jones, we have come
a long way, my friend.
We've been going a while.
We need – we want to drop
– we want to end this.
Yeah, we do want to end.
I just wanted to – I'm sorry
I'm mentioning it so late.
There's a new Hypercatcher,
Hypercatcher 2.0 that we've got
– that David has come back for –
he has been resurrected,
and there's all kinds of cool
features he's putting in there.
And I use Hypercatcher, I use it with my
team, my team consisting of Dreb Scott.
It's not really my team because
I don't want to 1099 him,
so I don't know who that guy is.
Yeah, it's Dreb somebody.
It's Dreb somebody.
And it looks cool.
So, you know, more development.
And we've had Hypercatcher
around since the very beginning,
and it's just a very invaluable tool for –
at least for my – for the podcast that
I do and others who are using it.
So I'm real happy about that.
So check that out, hypercatcher.
– is it dot – dot?
I thought it was dot I-O for some reason.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Hypercatcher – no, it's hypercatcher.com.
And – well, actually, the new
one is hypercatcher.studio.
Ah, that's it.
That's the back end.
That's where you want to be in the back.
And so I think it is –
The old one was studio.hypercatcher.com.
Yes.
So that's – so I should say he built
a new studio, the new back end.
Okay.
And he's using this 8-bit
font, which is very sketchy.
Yeah.
Very Nintendo.
It's – yes, thank you.
It's not – I don't know if it's Nintendo.
It's more like – like Prodigy.
Do you remember – Oh, Prodigy.
Do you remember Prodigy?
Barely, yeah.
Yeah, that was the Sears-owned,
kind of like America Online.
Sears.
Yeah, it was owned by Sears.
Yeah.
It was – Yeah, this looks – this looks like
– this font reminds me of the Apple IIe.
Yeah, like that too.
Yeah.
Or the color computer from Radio Shack.
Do you remember that one?
Uh-uh.
No, I did not remember.
I did not remember that.
That was before the TRS-80.
They had the color – I think
it was before the TRS-80.
I remember the TRS-80.
I still have my TRS-100, baby.
Do you still have a – the VIC-20?
Do you still have a VIC-20?
No.
Unfortunately, I don't have the VIC-20.
But the TRS-100 was the portable with
the, like, eight-line LCD screen,
and it ran on AA batteries.
It had a built-in modem, 300 baud.
I still have it.
Oh, nice.
Yeah.
I'll bring it on cam next time.
On cam?
Can you unbox it?
Yeah, sure.
The Hypercatcher Studio font is –
I figured out it's Oregon Trail.
Do you remember that game?
Is that what it's called?
Oregon Trail?
No, that was an old game.
It looks like the Oregon Trail
font from the Apple IIe days.
I was looking to see if I
could find the TRS-100.
That's somewhere in the closet.
Okay.
So, what's on deck for next week, Dave?
First of all, what are
you doing this weekend?
Just hanging out, chilling?
No, you got stuff, dude.
Oh, your vacation?
No, no, no.
We're getting ready for
my son's graduation.
He graduates from high
school on Wednesday.
So, we're going to have a big bash.
And so, is he mobile now, or?
Go to the doctor on Monday and to
see if he can put weight on his leg.
He's still on the walker right now.
Okay.
So, that's a big one.
We've got our fingers crossed.
Yes.
That he can get off the walker Monday in
time for his graduation party on Wednesday.
And then once he's mobile again,
then he can go take care of
his own shit again, right?
Yeah, then get off mob couch.
Yeah.
All right.
I have no idea what's going on next week.
But we'll see.
It feels like we have a lot
of movement in this area.
So, I'm really excited.
I'll probably be working with Alex
Gates on some of this video stuff.
Oh, cool.
And as well as the IPFS.
I don't know.
It just feels like from a
user standpoint, podcaster,
there's a lot more for me
to do all of a sudden.
Yeah.
Next week, I'm going to talk some more.
I've got a bunch.
I only made it halfway through the list
here of stuff I want to talk about.
So, next week, I do want to talk about some
stuff with – I've actually been talking
to a lot of podcast hosting companies over
the last two weeks about helping them do
submissions to the index
and that kind of thing.
So, I just want to let everybody know there's
a lot of interest and things are still
– like Podcasting 2.0 is front
of mind for a lot of people.
And, you know, we throw it all on the
floor and then scrape it up into piles and
throw scissors at things.
But the hosting companies, they do
actual product launches and rollouts.
Yeah.
So, you don't hear about
it until they happen.
But it's encouraging to let everybody
know that they are looking at things.
Well, thank you.
We'll talk about that.
Everybody, thank you very much for
participating in this fantastic experiment.
Thank you, chat room,
for being with us today.
Thank you, everyone, who is
implementing all of this fantastic,
crazy stuff that we're just
cutting each other up with.
And remember, podcasting is a slow grower,
but it grows consistently, consistently.
And with that, I bid you adieu, my friend.
All right, bro.
Have a good weekend.
And that's it for Podcasting 2.0.
We'll be back next week
with the board meeting.
Join us, please, right here at
Podcasting 2.0, the podcast.
You've been listening to Podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Go podcasting!
We have the boosts!